


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31200416</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0002-5151</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>66</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <MedlineDate>2019 Apr-Jun</MedlineDate>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Revista alergia Mexico (Tecamachalco, Puebla, Mexico : 1993)</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Rev Alerg Mex</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[Prevalence of asthma and symptoms association degree in the school population of Sierra Norte de Puebla].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>178-183</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.29262/ram.v66i2.539</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The prevalence of asthma in cities in the central part of Mexico ranges from 7% to 17%.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine the prevalence of asthma and to determine the degree of association of the symptoms with asthma as risk indicators for the diagnosis of the disease.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The &quot;Questionnaire for the Diagnosis of Asthma for Epidemiological Studies&quot; was applied to children who go to public elementary, middle and high schools of a population in &quot;Sierra Madre&quot;, to the north of Puebla.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">3387 answered questionnaires were obtained; 47.7% participants were male and 52.3% were female; the ages ranged from 3 to 19 years of age, finding a general prevalence of asthma of 7.4%. The findings go from 9.4% of chest tightness to 28% of predominantly nocturnal coughing. Recurrent wheezing, chest tightness and recurrent coughing had the highest degree of association with asthma and formed the main risk indicators for the diagnosis in patients that are not identified as asthmatic.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The prevalence of the diagnosis of asthma was 7.4%, the individual prevalence of the symptoms is usually higher. The symptoms that showed the highest strength of association with asthma are the ones suggested by the diagnostic possibility of asthma.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Mancilla-Hernández</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Eleazar</ForeName>
                    <Initials>E</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Centro de Investigación en el Área de la Salud, Puebla, Puebla, México. manele05@yahoo.com.mx.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Hernández-Morales</LastName>
                    <ForeName>María Rocío</ForeName>
                    <Initials>MR</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>González-Solórzano</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Evaristo</ForeName>
                    <Initials>E</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>spa</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Prevalencia de asma y grado de asociación de los síntomas en población escolar de la sierra norte de Puebla.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Mexico</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Rev Alerg Mex</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9438824</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0002-5151</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa">
            <AbstractText>Antecedentes: La prevalencia del asma en ciudades del centro de México oscila entre 7 y 17 %. Objetivos: Determinar la prevalencia de asma y grado de asociación de los síntomas con el asma, como indicadores de riesgo para el diagnóstico de la enfermedad. Método: Se aplicó el cuestionario Diagnóstico de Asma para Estudios Epidemiológicos en niños de escuelas primarias, secundarias y preparatorias oficiales, no particulares, de una población de la sierra madre del norte de Puebla. Resultados: Se obtuvieron 3387 cuestionarios contestados, 47.7 % del sexo masculino y 52.3 % del femenino, las edades oscilaron entre 3 y 19 años de edad; la prevalencia general de asma fue de 7.4 %. Se encontró 9.4 % de opresión torácica y 28 % de tos de predominio nocturno. Las sibilancias recurrentes, la opresión torácica y la tos recurrente tuvieron el mayor grado de asociación con el asma y constituyeron los principales indicadores de riesgo para el diagnóstico en pacientes no identificados como asmáticos. Conclusiones: La prevalencia del diagnóstico de asma fue de 7.4 %; la prevalencia individual de los síntomas habitualmente fue mayor. Los síntomas que mostraron mayor fuerza de asociación con el asma son los que sugieren la posibilidad diagnóstica de asma.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Asthma</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis of asthma</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Symptoms of asthma</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200416</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29262/ram.v66i2.539</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

