


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31199318</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2561-326X</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>3</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                        <Day>09</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>JMIR formative research</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Form Res</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Predisposing and Motivational Factors Related to Social Network Sites Use: Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>e12248</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/12248</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Social network sites (SNSs) have been defined as Web services that involve creating a private or semiprivate profile. Through these services, adolescents and adults can maintain and create new relationships. Adolescents, in particular, can be considered the main users of these sites as they spend a lot of time on SNSs. In using SNSs, individuals can exert greater control over the conversation and on the information shared, which is associated with a desire for self-presentation. Moreover, the need for self-presentation is related to personality traits such as those of the Big Five, namely extraversion, neuroticism, openness to experience, agreeableness, and conscientiousness, as well as emotional stability, introversion, narcissism, and motivational aspects. The latter are usually linked to an underlying social purpose that might predispose an individual to using SNSs, with the intent of satisfying particular needs, such as belongingness and interpersonal competency.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Using the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) method, this study aimed to present a systematic review of the scientific literature regarding the predisposing factors related to the Big Five personality traits and motivational aspects associated with the use of SNSs, for both adolescents (12-19 years) and adults (&gt;20 years).</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A search ranging from 2007 to 2017 was conducted through the academic database of Google Scholar and PsycINFO, in which the following terms and their derivatives were considered: predisposing factors, personality traits, Big Five model, self-esteem, self-presentation, interpersonal competency, social network site, Facebook, motivation, five-factor model, use, abuse, and addiction. Based on a defined list of inclusion and exclusion criteria, a total of 9 papers were finally included in the review.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Our findings identified 3 main personality traits to be of greater value: extraversion, neuroticism, and openness to experience. Extraversion was a good predictor of motivation and SNS use, whereas the latter trait showed relevance for age differences. All 3 features further played a role in gender differences. Apart from extraversion, the self-presentational motive was also related to narcissism, whereas the need to belong presented an association with agreeableness and neuroticism. Further underlining the social value behind SNS use, people perceived interpersonal competency as being related to Facebook use intensity.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Extraversion was recognized as the main forerunner for SNS use and motivation for use. Neuroticism seems to be related to an attempt at compensating for difficulties in real-life social contexts. Openness to experiences has a strong valence for both adults and older adults since SNSs are still perceived as a novelty. Moreover, gender differences in SNS usage were observed to be the product of differences in motivation. Implications and limitations of the study were discussed.</AbstractText>
                <CopyrightInformation>©Elisa Mancinelli, Giulia Bassi, Silvia Salcuni. Originally published in JMIR Formative Research (http://formative.jmir.org), 09.06.2019.</CopyrightInformation>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
                    <LastName>Mancinelli</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Elisa</ForeName>
                    <Initials>E</Initials>
                    <Identifier Source="ORCID">http://orcid.org/0000-0003-2089-3507</Identifier>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of General Psychology, University of Padua, Padua, Italy.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
                    <LastName>Bassi</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Giulia</ForeName>
                    <Initials>G</Initials>
                    <Identifier Source="ORCID">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-7239-3021</Identifier>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Human Inspired Technology, Department of Developmental and Socialization Psychology, University of Padua, Padua, Italy.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
                    <LastName>Salcuni</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Silvia</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                    <Identifier Source="ORCID">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-1798-5761</Identifier>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Developmental and Socialization Psychology, University of Padua, Padua, Italy.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>09</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Canada</Country>
            <MedlineTA>JMIR Form Res</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101726394</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>2561-326X</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescents</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adults</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">individual differences</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motivation</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social networks</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2018</Year>
                <Month>09</Month>
                <Day>20</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>04</Month>
                <Day>13</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>03</Month>
                <Day>23</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31199318</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">v3i2e12248</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/12248</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

