


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31200413</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0002-5151</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>66</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <MedlineDate>2019 Apr-Jun</MedlineDate>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Revista alergia Mexico (Tecamachalco, Puebla, Mexico : 1993)</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Rev Alerg Mex</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[The prevalence of allergic rhinitis and atopic dermatitis in late adolescents differs according to their gender].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>147-153</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.29262/ram.v66i2.521</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">In Mexico, there are very few studies aimed at establishing the prevalence of allergic rhinitis (AR) and atopic dermatitis (AD) in late adolescents.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine the prevalence of allergic rhinitis and atopic dermatitis in late adolescents and compare it according to their gender.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional study that included 1992 15 to 18 year old adolescents who were recruited through a stratified and randomized probabilistic sample by clusters. The prevalence of AR (allergic rhinitis) and AD (atopic dermatitis) was identified with the questionnaire of &quot;The International Study of Asthma and Allergies in Childhood&quot;.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">1056 (53%) women and 936 (47%) men were included in the study. The prevalence of AR was 9.0% (95% CI = 7.8% - 10.4%); the frequency was higher in women (6.7% versus 11.1%, p = 0.001). The symptoms of rhinitis plus conjunctivitis predominated in women (16.0% versus 23.1%, p &lt; 0.0001). The prevalence of AD was 5.2% (95% CI = 4.3% - 6.2%) and, once again, it was more frequent in women (7.7% versus 2.4%, p &lt; 0.0001). The main factors associated with AR and AD were the female gender and a history of family atopic allergic diseases (p &lt; 0.001).</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">There was a significant difference in the prevalence of AR and AD according to gender in late adolescents; women were most affected. In addition, a history of family atopic allergic diseases was another risk factor that was linked to both diseases.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>González-Mendoza</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Tania</ForeName>
                    <Initials>T</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Nuevo Hospital Civil de Guadalajara Dr. Juan I. Menchaca, Servicio de Alergia e Inmunología Clínica, Guadalajara, Jalisco, México. tglezm@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Bedolla-Barajas</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Martín</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Bedolla-Pulido</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Tonatiuh Ramsés</ForeName>
                    <Initials>TR</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Morales-Romero</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Jaime</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Pulido-Guillén</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Norma Angélica</ForeName>
                    <Initials>NA</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Lerma-Partida</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Silvia</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Meza-López</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Carlos</ForeName>
                    <Initials>C</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>spa</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>La prevalencia de rinitis alérgica y dermatitis atópica en adolescentes tardíos difiere de acuerdo con el sexo.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Mexico</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Rev Alerg Mex</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9438824</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0002-5151</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa">
            <AbstractText>Antecedentes: En México son escasos los estudios encaminados a establecer la prevalencia de la rinitis alérgica y la dermatitis atópica en adolescentes tardíos. Objetivo: Determinar la prevalencia de rinitis alérgica y dermatitis atópica en adolescentes tardíos y compararla conforme el sexo. Métodos: Estudio transversal de 1992 adolescentes de 15 a 18 años, reclutados mediante muestreo probabilístico por conglomerados, estratificado y aleatorizado. Las prevalencias de rinitis alérgica y dermatitis atópica se identificaron con el cuestionario propuesto en The Internacional Study of Asthma and Allergies in Childhood. Resultados: Se incluyeron 1056 mujeres (53 %) y 936 hombres (47 %). La prevalencia de rinitis alérgica fue de 9.0 % (IC 95 % = 7.8-10.4); la frecuencia fue mayor en las mujeres (6.7 % versus 11.1 %, p = 0.001). Los síntomas de rinitis más conjuntivitis predominaron en las mujeres (16.0 % versus 23.1 %, p &lt; 0.0001). La prevalencia de dermatitis atópica fue de 5.2 % (IC 95 % = 4.3-6.2); fue más frecuente en las mujeres (7.7 % versus 2.4 %, p &lt; 0.0001). Los principales factores asociados con rinitis alérgica y dermatitis atópica fueron sexo femenino y atopia familiar (p &lt; 0.001). Conclusiones: Se registró diferencia significativa en la prevalencia de rinitis alérgica y dermatitis atópica conforme el sexo en los adolescentes tardíos; las mujeres fueron las más afectadas. La atopia familiar fue otro factor asociado.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Allergic rhinitis</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atopic dermatitis</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Late adolescent</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200413</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29262/ram.v66i2.521</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

