


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198962</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-994X</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                        <Day>14</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Nicotine &amp; tobacco research : official journal of the Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Nicotine Tob. Res.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Exposure to multi-media tobacco marketing and product use among youth: A longitudinal analysis.</ArticleTitle>
            <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">ntz096</ELocationID>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/ntr/ntz096</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Tobacco companies continue to reach youth through direct-to-consumer marketing which has been associated with overall tobacco use. We examine how exposure to these marketing activities influences product-specific use behaviors.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We analyzed data from 10,081 youth (aged 12-18) who participated in Waves 1 and 2 (2013-2015) of the Population Assessment of Tobacco and Health (PATH) Study. Participants reported past 6-month tobacco coupon receipt and online tobacco marketing engagement, and susceptibility to, ever and currentuse of cigarette, e-cigarettes, cigars, smokeless tobacco, and hookah. Weighted multivariable logistic regression examined Wave 1 predictors of coupon receipt at Wave 2, and associations between coupon receipt, online engagement, and past 30-day use of different tobacco products.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Youth received tobacco coupons at one (9.7%) or both waves (1.2%) and 11.1% engaged with online tobacco marketing. Coupon receipt and online marketing engagement at Wave 1 predicted Wave 2 coupon receipt among susceptible-never, ever-but-not-current, and current tobacco users (p&lt;0.05). Coupon receipt and online engagement at Wave 1 was positively associated with past 30-day use of cigarettes, e-cigarettes, cigars, smokeless tobacco, and hookah at Wave 2 (p&lt;0.05). The relationships were stronger for those who received coupons at both waves or engaged with more sources of online marketing.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Tobacco direct-to-consumer marketing is reaching youth. Repeated exposure to these marketing activities within and across media is associated with use of different tobacco products. New policies and strong enforcement of existing regulations prohibiting these illegal marketing tactics are critical to protect youth from future tobacco use.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Tobacco companies utilize coupons and online engagement activities to increase brand awareness, knowledge and sales of their products. These kind of marketing activities can be influential among youth at a time when they may develop tobacco use behaviors. Our findings suggest that tobacco companies may be targeting at-risk youth through cross-media marketing activities. The findings also indicate that exposure to these marketing activities predicts subsequent use of different tobacco products, with suggestive dose-response relationships. Increased regulations are needed to protect youth from these marketing activities.</AbstractText>
                <CopyrightInformation>Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 2019. This work is written by (a) US Government employee(s) and is in the public domain in the US.</CopyrightInformation>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Choi</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Kelvin</ForeName>
                    <Initials>K</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities Division of Intramural Research Rockville Pike, Bethesda, MD.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Rose</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Shyanika W</ForeName>
                    <Initials>SW</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Truth Initiative Schroeder Institute, Washington, DC.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Zhou</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Yitong</ForeName>
                    <Initials>Y</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Truth Initiative Schroeder Institute, Washington, DC.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Rahman</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Basmah</ForeName>
                    <Initials>B</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Truth Initiative Schroeder Institute, Washington, DC.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Hair</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName>
                    <Initials>E</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Truth Initiative Schroeder Institute, Washington, DC.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, Baltimore, MD Wolfe Street Baltimore, MD.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>14</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>England</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Nicotine Tob Res</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9815751</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>1462-2203</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2018</Year>
                <Month>12</Month>
                <Day>14</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198962</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">5518940</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntz096</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

