


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198926</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1463-9084</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                        <Day>14</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Physical chemistry chemical physics : PCCP</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Phys Chem Chem Phys</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Synthesis of Pt@TiO<sub>2</sub> nanocomposite electrocatalysts for enhanced methanol oxidation by hydrophobic nanoreactor templating.</ArticleTitle>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/c9cp00502a</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>In this work Pt@TiO2 nanocomposite electrocatalysts for methanol oxidation were synthesized using a one-pot process by hydrophobic nanoreactor templating. TiO2 was used as a support material for the platinum nanoparticles, thereby providing strong metal-support interactions. The Pt@TiO2 electrocatalyst consists of a monolayer of spherical superstructures comprising finely dispersed platinum nanoparticles in a crystalline TiO2 matrix as revealed by high resolution (scanning) transmission electron microscopy (HR-TEM and HR-STEM) combined with energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX), electron diffraction and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). The Pt@TiO2 electrocatalyst showed high methanol oxidation activity, exceeding the activity of a commercial Pt/C catalyst by a factor of 2.5, as well as a cathodically shifted methanol oxidation peak. The increased methanol oxidation activity of Pt@TiO2 was attributed to its enhanced CO oxidation ability, an undesired intermediate, which is formed during methanol oxidation and poisons the Pt-surface. Indeed, CO stripping experiments confirmed that CO oxidation takes place at lower potentials in the case of Pt@TiO2, leading to a cathodic shift of the CO oxidation peak by 100 mV compared to a commercial Pt/C reference catalyst. Insights into the mechanism of methanol oxidation on Pt@TiO2 were found by comparison of methanol oxidation in different electrolytes. It was found that methanol oxidation via the CO-route is more pronounced on Pt@TiO2 than on Pt/C. The improved activity for CO oxidation resulted thereby in a better catalyst performance, especially at low potentials, and an increased stability, as demonstrated by chronoamperometry. The long-term stability of the catalyst was further addressed by accelerated stress tests (AST), which showed that the superior catalytic activity is retained even after 30 000 potential cycles.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Unmüssig</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Tobias</ForeName>
                    <Initials>T</Initials>
                    <Identifier Source="ORCID">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-6108-068X</Identifier>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Institute for Inorganic and Analytical Chemistry, University of Freiburg, Albertstrasse 21, 79104 Freiburg, Germany. anna.fischer@ac.uni-freiburg.de and FMF - Freiburg Materials Research Center, University of Freiburg, Stefan-Meier-Straße 19, 79104 Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Melke</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Julia</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                    <Identifier Source="ORCID">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-5574-0207</Identifier>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Institute for Inorganic and Analytical Chemistry, University of Freiburg, Albertstrasse 21, 79104 Freiburg, Germany. anna.fischer@ac.uni-freiburg.de and FMF - Freiburg Materials Research Center, University of Freiburg, Stefan-Meier-Straße 19, 79104 Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Fischer</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Anna</ForeName>
                    <Initials>A</Initials>
                    <Identifier Source="ORCID">http://orcid.org/0000-0003-4567-3009</Identifier>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Institute for Inorganic and Analytical Chemistry, University of Freiburg, Albertstrasse 21, 79104 Freiburg, Germany. anna.fischer@ac.uni-freiburg.de and FMF - Freiburg Materials Research Center, University of Freiburg, Stefan-Meier-Straße 19, 79104 Freiburg, Germany and FIT - Freiburg Center for Interactive Materials and Bioinspired Technologies, University of Freiburg, Georges-Köhler-Allee 105, 79110 Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>14</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>England</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Phys Chem Chem Phys</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>100888160</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>1463-9076</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198926</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c9cp00502a</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

