


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198900</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2501-2533</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>63</Volume>
                    <Issue>1</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <MedlineDate>2019 Jan-Mar</MedlineDate>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Romanian journal of ophthalmology</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Rom J Ophthalmol</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>The effect of corneal cross-linking on the anterior and posterior parameters of the cornea: A prospective repeatability study.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>68-74</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText><b>Objective.</b> To determine the effect of corneal cross-linking (CXL) on the anterior and posterior corneal indices in terms of their repeatability and change as measured with Pentacam. <b>Methods.</b> Thirty eyes of 30 patients with progressive keratoconus undergoing CXL were enrolled. At each visit (pre-CXL, 6 and 12 months after CXL), imaging were done twice, one hour apart to determine the repeatability index (RI) and intra-class correlation coefficient (ICC). For same session measurements, we computed the intra-session repeatability. We also calculated 4 measures of change by subtracting baseline from 1-year results and determined the repeatability of measures of change. <b>Results.</b> There was no significant difference between the intra-session RI at baseline, 6 months, and 12 months for anterior Kmax-3mm (P=0.609), anterior Kmin-3mm (P=0.548), Kmax-8mm (P=0.860), posterior Kmax-3mm (P=0.717), posterior Kmin-3mm (P=0.548), Q-value-6mm (P=0.890), central corneal thickness (P=0.751), minimum corneal thickness (P=0.787), or anterior chamber depth (P=0.760). The ICCs for these indices were higher than 0.9. For keratoconus indices, there was no significant difference between the intra-session RI at baseline and follow-ups (P&gt;0.05), and the ICC were higher than 0.9 except for baseline and 6-month index of height asymmetry (IHA). The ICC for all 1-year measures of change were more than 0.75 except for posterior corneal indices and IHA. <b>Conclusion.</b> Pentacam repeatability of different indices is not affected by CXL. However, the change of indices showed high variance, which should be taken into consideration, especially in systematic reviews because inter-study differences can be due to low repeatability of the measures of change.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Hashemi</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Hassan</ForeName>
                    <Initials>H</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Noor Research Center for Ophthalmic Epidemiology, Noor Eye Hospital, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Mehravaran</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Shiva</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>ASCEND Center for Biomedical Research, Morgan State University, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Asgari</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Soheila</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Noor Ophthalmology Research Center, Noor Eye Hospital, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Romania</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Rom J Ophthalmol</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101677459</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>2457-4325</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corneal cross-linking</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corneal index</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reliability study </Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198900</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

