


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198898</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2501-2533</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>63</Volume>
                    <Issue>1</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <MedlineDate>2019 Jan-Mar</MedlineDate>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Romanian journal of ophthalmology</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Rom J Ophthalmol</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Evaluation of semi-preloaded intraocular lens delivery system.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>56-60</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText><b>Purpose:</b> In this study, we aimed to evaluate the single surgeon experience of semi-preloaded intraocular lens (IOL) delivery system. <b>Methods:</b> Phacoemulsification was performed under topical anesthesia by temporal clear corneal incision. CT Lucia hydrophobic IOL was injected through semi- preloaded IOL system in the capsular bag. Two hundred patients (200 eyes) were included in the study. The main outcome measures were ease of implantation, intraoperative and postoperative complications, postoperative centration, and visual acuity. Data on successful implantation and complications were collected prospectively. <b>Results:</b> Correct IOL delivery was achieved in 193 out of 200 patients (96.5%). Four patients (2%) required intrawound rotation of the injector to place the leading haptic in the capsular bag. Two patients (1%) had anteroposterior rotation of the IOL and one patient (0.5%) had total posterior rotation of IOL. Other problems noted were trapped trailing haptic (n=2,1%), improper loading of IOL (n=3,1.5%) and stretch marks on the optic of IOL (n=4,2%). None of the patients had iris trauma or posterior capsular rupture during the implantation and manipulation of the IOL. The mean incision size after completion of implantation of IOL was 2.82 mm (+ 0.02), which achieved sutureless closure. None of the patients developed postoperative infection. <b>Conclusion:</b> Implantation of CT Lucia 601 PY IOL with the semi preloaded system led to minor complications and gave satisfactory visual results.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Rajesh</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Rajesh</ForeName>
                    <Initials>R</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Vasantrao Naik Government Medical, College, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Romania</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Rom J Ophthalmol</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101677459</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>2457-4325</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CT Lucia</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intraocular lenses</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phacoemulsification</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">preloaded intraocular lens</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198898</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

