


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198732</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">2249-4863</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>8</Volume>
                    <Issue>5</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>May</Month>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Journal of family medicine and primary care</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>J Family Med Prim Care</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Comparing serum lead level in drug abuse pregnant women with non-addicted pregnant mothers referring to Shiraz university hospitals in 2017-2018.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>1653-1657</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_36_19</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="Introduction" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In recent decades, there are multiple reports of lead poisoning in drug abusers in Iran and other Middle East countries. The lead in the mother's blood can cause many dangerous, harmful effects on the mother and the fetus. Therefore, in this study, we evaluated the blood lead level (BLL) in pregnant women who were an illegal drug user and compared it with pregnant women who did not use these agents.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Method" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A cross-sectional study was conducted among 60 pregnant women referred to Shiraz Hazrat Zinab and Hafez Hospitals. All pregnant women with a history of any drug abuse were sampled. Two pregnant women without any history of drug abuse were sampled for each pregnant mother with a history of drug abuse on the same day. To check BLL, 5 cc blood sample of all participants sent to a reference laboratory. BLLs have been assessed by atomic absorption spectrophotometry with GBC Avanta, and all reports were confirmed by a specific pathologist. The data were completed with maternal demographic information and infants' anthropometric indices. Data analysis was performed using SPSS software version 24, and the significance was 0.05.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Results" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There was a significant difference in BLL among pregnant women with and without drug abuse history (9.91 ± 26.2 and 2.95 ± 0.7, respectively) (P-value: 0.001). The prevalence of lead levels of more than 5 μg/dl in mothers with and without substance abuse was 20% and 7.5%, respectively. Anthropometric indices, Apgar score, and gestational age in the mothers with a history of drug abuse were significantly lower than the control group (a significant level less than 0.05).</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Conclusion" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The level of lead in pregnant women taking illegal drugs is higher than that of the control group who do not have a history of illegal drug abuse. On the other hand, it is likely that increased serum levels of lead with fetal complications and maternal health threats childbirth and clinical outcomes during childbirth.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Rezaie</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Mehrdad</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine and Pediatric Medicine, Neonatology Research Center, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Abolhassanzadeh</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Seyedeh Zarrin</ForeName>
                    <Initials>SZ</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Student Research Committee, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Haghighinejad</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Hourvash</ForeName>
                    <Initials>H</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>India</Country>
            <MedlineTA>J Family Med Prim Care</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101610082</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>2249-4863</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood lead level</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">poisoning</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pregnancy</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">substance abuse</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
        <CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198732</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_36_19</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">JFMPC-8-1653</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6559079</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

