


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198659</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">2196-5226</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>14</Volume>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>GMS hygiene and infection control</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>GMS Hyg Infect Control</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Bacterial contamination of automated MRI contrast injectors in clinical routine.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>Doc05</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3205/dgkh000321</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText><b>Aim:</b> To quantify the frequency of bacterial contamination of the injected contrast agent/saline solution by an automated contrast injection system, and to evaluate whether usage of a novel tube system can reduce it. <b>Methods:</b> For bacterial contamination quantification two identical automated piston pump MRI contrast injectors were used in combination with a standard tube system. 3-5 ml of the contrast agent/saline solution was collected from the system prior to its connection to the patients' venous cannula in 104 consecutive patients. To test, whether a novel tube system reduces contamination, a tube system with shielded screw connections was used with the same contrast injectors and contrast agent/saline samples were collected in further 101 patients. Specimens were microbiologically analyzed. Frequencies of contamination were compared using Fisher exact test. <b>Results:</b> With the standard tube system, bacterial contamination was observed in 5.8% (6 out of 104 specimens). With the novel tube system, contamination was observed in 2.0% (2 out of 101 specimens, p=0.280). <i>Staphylococcus epidermidis</i> was the most common germ (5 cases) followed by <i>Micrococcus luteus</i> (2 cases) and <i>Oligella ureolytica</i> (1 case). <b>Conclusion:</b> Bacterial contaminations of MRI contrast injectors occurred in a non-negligible frequency especially with <i>S. epidermidis</i>. A trend towards reduced bacterial contamination was seen when a novel tube system with shielded screw connections was used.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Goebel</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Juliane</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic and Interventional Radiology and Neuroradiology, University Hospital Essen, Germany.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Steinmann</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Joerg</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Hygiene, Medical Microbiology and Infectiology, Paracelsus Medical University, Hospital Nuernberg, Germany.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Institute of Medical Microbiology, University Hospital Essen, Germany.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Heintschel von Heinegg</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Evelyn</ForeName>
                    <Initials>E</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Institute of Medical Microbiology, University Hospital Essen, Germany.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Hestermann</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Tobias</ForeName>
                    <Initials>T</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic and Interventional Radiology and Neuroradiology, University Hospital Essen, Germany.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Nassenstein</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Kai</ForeName>
                    <Initials>K</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic and Interventional Radiology and Neuroradiology, University Hospital Essen, Germany.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>17</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Germany</Country>
            <MedlineTA>GMS Hyg Infect Control</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101609519</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>2196-5226</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="ger">
            <AbstractText><b>Ziel:</b> Es sollte die Häufigkeit der bakteriellen Verunreinigung des injizierten Kontrastmittel-/Kochsalzgemisches in der klinischen MRT-Routine erfasst und untersucht werden, ob selbige durch Verwendung eines optimierten Kontrastmittelinjektorsystems reduziert werden kann.<b>Methoden:</b> Es wurde ein automatisches Kolbenpumpen-Kontrastmittelinjektorsystem kombiniert mit einem Standard MRT-Infusionsschlauchsystem verwendet und vor der Ankopplung an die venöse Verweilkanüle von 104 konsekutiven Patienten 3–5 ml des Kontrastmittel-/Kochsalzgemisches entnommen. Zudem wurde bei weiteren 101 Patienten ein optimiertes Infusionsschlauchsystem mit versenkten Schraubenkontakten verwendet und ebenfalls 3–5 ml des Kontrastmittel-/Kochsalzgemisches gesammelt. Die Proben wurden mikrobiologisch analysiert und die Kontaminationshäufigkeit mittels Fisher’s Exact Test verglichen.<b>Ergebnisse:</b> Beim Standard-Infusionsschlauchsystem fand sich in 5,8% (6 von 104 Proben) und beim optimierten Infusionsschlauchsystem in 2,0% (2 von 101 Proben) eine bakterielle Verunreinigung (p=0.280). Am häufigsten war <i>Staphylococcus epidermidis</i> anzüchtbar (n=5), seltener <i>Micrococcus luteus</i> (n=2) und <i>Oligella ureolytica</i> (n=1).<b>Schlussfolgerungen:</b> Eine bakterielle Kontamination des Kontrastmittelinjektorsystems, speziell mit <i>Staphylococcus epidermidis</i> trat in nicht unerheblicher Frequenz auf und konnte durch die Verwendung eines optimierten Infusionsschlauchsystems tendenziell gesenkt werden.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MR imaging</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">automated contrast injector</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bacterial contamination</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">contrast agent</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hygiene</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
        <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198659</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3205/dgkh000321</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">dgkh000321</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">Doc05</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6545436</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

