


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198633</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">2167-8359</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>7</Volume>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>PeerJ</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>PeerJ</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Exploring the feasibility, sustainability and the benefits of the GrACE + GAIT exercise programme in the residential aged care setting.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>e6973</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7717/peerj.6973</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="Background" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The feasibility and benefits of a 24-week targeted progressive supervised resistance and weight-bearing exercise programme (Group Aged Care Exercise + GAIT (GrACE + GAIT)) in the residential aged care (RAC) setting was investigated as very little peer-reviewed research has been conducted in relation to exercise programmes of this duration in this cohort.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Methods" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A quasi-experimental study design consisting of two groups (control and exercise) explored a 24-week targeted progressive supervised resistance and weight-bearing exercise programme (GrACE + GAIT) in two RAC facilities in Northern New South Wales, Australia. A total of 42 adults consented to participate from a total of 68 eligible residents (61.7%). The primary outcome measures were feasibility and sustainability of the exercise programme via intervention uptake, session adherence, attrition, acceptability and adverse events. Secondary measures included gait speed and the spatio-temporal parameters of gait, handgrip muscle strength and sit to stand performance.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Results" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Twenty-three residents participated in the exercise intervention (mean (SD) 85.4 (8.1) years, 15 females) and 19 in the control group (87.4 (6.6) years 13 females). Exercise adherence was 79.3%, with 65% of exercise participants attending ≥70% of the sessions; 100% of those originally enrolled completed the programme and strongly agreed with the programme acceptability. Zero exercise-related adverse events were reported. ANCOVA results indicated that post-intervention gait speed significantly increased (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.001) with an 18.8% increase in gait speed (m/s).</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Discussion" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The GrACE + GAIT programme was shown to be feasible and significantly improve adults living in RAC facilities gait speed, handgrip strength and sit to stand performance. These results suggest that the GrACE + GAIT programme is suitable for use in the RAC sector and that it has the potential to reduce disability and improve function and quality of life of the residents.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Fien</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Samantha</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>School of Health, Medical and Applied Sciences, CQUniversity, Mackay, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Health Science and Medicine, Bond University, Robina, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Henwood</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Tim</ForeName>
                    <Initials>T</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Southern Cross Care, North Plympton, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Climstein</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Mike</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>School of Health and Human Sciences, Southern Cross University, Gold Coast, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Water Based Research Unit, Bond University, Robina, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Physical Activity, Lifestyle, Ageing and Wellbeing Faculty Research Group, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Rathbone</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Evelyne</ForeName>
                    <Initials>E</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Health Science and Medicine, Bond University, Robina, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Keogh</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Justin W L</ForeName>
                    <Initials>JWL</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Health Science and Medicine, Bond University, Robina, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Human Potential Centre, Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Kasturba Medical College, Mangalore, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>04</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>PeerJ</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101603425</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>2167-8359</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ageing</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Geriatrics</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Walking</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
        <CoiStatement>Justin W.L. Keogh and Mike Climstein are Academic Editors for PeerJ. Timothy Henwood is the Group Manager, Connected Living—Community Wellness and Lifestyle of Southern Cross Care (SA &amp; NT) Inc., Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2018</Year>
                <Month>09</Month>
                <Day>05</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>04</Month>
                <Day>16</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198633</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.6973</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">6973</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6555397</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

