


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198530</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">2041-2851</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>11</Volume>
                    <Issue>3</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>AoB PLANTS</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>AoB Plants</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>The morphometrics of autopolyploidy: insignificant differentiation among sexual-apomictic cytotypes.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>plz028</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/aobpla/plz028</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Polyploidization of the plant genome affects the phenotype of individuals including their morphology, i.e. size and form. In autopolyploids, we expect mainly nucleotypic effects, from a number of monoploid genomes (i.e. chromosome sets) or genome size, seen from an increase in size or dimension of the polyploids compared with the diploids (or lower ploids). To identify nucleotypic effects, confounding effects of hybridity (observed in allopolyploids), postpolyploidization processes or environmental effects need to be considered. We morphometrically analysed five ploidy cytotypes of the sexual-apomictic species <i>Potentilla puberula</i> cultivated <i>ex situ</i> under the same experimental conditions. Sexuals are mainly tetraploid, while higher ploidy (penta- to octoploidy) is typically associated with the expression of apomixis. The cytotypes likely arose via autopolyploidization although historic involvement of another species in the origin of apomicts cannot be fully ruled out, suggested by a slight molecular differentiation among reproductive modes. We (i) revisited molecular differentiation using amplified fragment length polymorphisms and performed a morphometric analysis to test (ii) if cytotypes are morphologically differentiated from each other and (iii) if the size of individuals is related to their ploidy. Weak molecular differentiation of sexual versus apomictic individuals was confirmed. Cytotypes and reproductive modes were also morphologically poorly differentiated from each other, i.e. apomicts largely resampled the variation of the sexuals and did not exhibit a unique morphology. Overall size of individuals increased moderately but significantly with ploidy (ca. 14 % in the comparison of octo- with tetraploids). The results support an autopolyploid origin of the <i>P. puberula</i> apomicts and suggest a nucleotypic effect on overall plant size. We discuss taxonomic consequences of the results in the context of data on reproductive relationships among cytotypes and their ecological preferences and evolutionary origin, and conclude that cytotypes are best treated as intraspecific variants within a single species.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Bigl</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Karin</ForeName>
                    <Initials>K</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacognosy, Pharmacobotany, University of Vienna, Althanstrasse, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Paule</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Juraj</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Botany and Molecular Evolution, Senckenberg Research Institute &amp; Natural History Museum Frankfurt, Senckenberganlage, Frankfurt/Main, Germany.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Dobeš</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Christoph</ForeName>
                    <Initials>C</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacognosy, Pharmacobotany, University of Vienna, Althanstrasse, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>04</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>England</Country>
            <MedlineTA>AoB Plants</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101539425</NlmUniqueID>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AFLPs</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Potentilla puberula</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rosaceae</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apomixis</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">morphology</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polyploidy</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reproduction</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sexuality</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2018</Year>
                <Month>12</Month>
                <Day>13</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>03</Month>
                <Day>11</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>22</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198530</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aobpla/plz028</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">plz028</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6548344</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

