


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198460</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">1857-9655</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>7</Volume>
                    <Issue>9</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>May</Month>
                        <Day>15</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Open access Macedonian journal of medical sciences</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Open Access Maced J Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Short-Term Outcome of Multi-Ligament Knee Injury among Sudanese Patients.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>1486-1493</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3889/oamjms.2019.282</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Multi-ligament knee injury is the state of having two or more of the major knee ligaments, namely: the anterior cruciate ligament (ACL), the posterior cruciate ligament (PCL), the medial collateral ligament (MCL), the lateral collateral ligament (LCL), the posteromedial corner (PMC), and the posterolateral corner (PLC). The knee is a hinge joint; this dictates two direction movements on the y-axis plane. The knee joints carry the weight load of the body uniquely. The role of the knee ligaments is not conserved only to maintain knee in a rigid position while standing, but also orchestrates the biomechanics of knee motion in harmony. Multi-ligament knee injury is very rare (incidence &lt; 10:10,000 of trauma cases). Patients with multiple ligaments injuries of the knee become disabled for a long period. This disability rises from the pain and stiffness of the knee joint. A disability that might be associated with increased frequencies of sick leave from work, or much more dire consequences, such as quitting a job or being relieved of duty.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To assess the functional outcome of the knee of patients with a multi-ligament knee injury after treatment using a standard scoring system and to determine the recovery rates of each treatment option to a multi-ligament knee injury.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">it is a cross-sectional study conducted from January 2018 to January 2019. All patients with multi-ligament knee injuries that were diagnosed by MRI, and underwent reconstruction surgeries or on the waiting list, at Ribat University Hospital and Alyaa Specialized Hospital, Alkuwiti specialised hospital, and Haj Alsafi Hospital for the past 2 years were included. Lyshlome knee scoring scale was used to assess the functional outcome of each patient.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">24 patients were enrolled in this study (16 had reconstruction surgery, 8 did not). 3 had excellent outcome (LKSS = 95 - 100), 8 of them had good score (LKSS = 84-94), 5 had fair outcome (LKSS = 65-83). All those who did not have reconstruction had a poor score (LKSS &lt; 64).</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Reconstruction of multi-ligament knee injury shows a good outcome than it was left alone. Post-operative physiotherapy increases the potential of reconstruction. While our data is limited because of the rare condition, we plan to expand our study area to include a larger sample size. We also recommend extending the post-operative physiotherapy to improve the outcome of a multi-ligament knee injury.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Ali</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Amin Ahmed</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>University of Khartoum, Khartoum, Sudan.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Abdelwahab</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Mohamed Babiker</ForeName>
                    <Initials>MB</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>National Ribat University, Khartoum, Sudan.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Macedonia</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Open Access Maced J Med Sci</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101662294</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>1857-9655</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACL</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LCL</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MCL</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multiligament knee injury</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PCL</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sports medicine</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sudanese knee reconstruction outcome</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>02</Month>
                <Day>28</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>05</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>06</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198460</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3889/oamjms.2019.282</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">OAMJMS-7-1486</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6542394</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

