


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198432</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">1741-427X</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>2019</Volume>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Evidence-based complementary and alternative medicine : eCAM</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Evid Based Complement Alternat Med</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Methanolic Extract of <i>Artemia salina</i> Eggs and Various Fractions in Different Solvents Contain Potent Compounds That Decrease Cell Viability of Colon and Skin Cancer Cell Lines and Show Antibacterial Activity against <i>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</i>.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>9528256</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2019/9528256</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText><i>Artemia salina,</i> crustaceans of class Branchiopoda and order Anostraca, are living and reproducing only in highly saline natural lakes and in other reservoirs where sea water is evaporated to produce salt. <i>Artemia salina</i> eggs can be purchased from pet stores, where they are sold as tropical fish food and a ready source for hatching shrimp. In the current study, methanolic crude extracts and various fractions of <i>Artemia salina</i> eggs extracted in other solvents were tested for effects on cell viability of human colorectal cancer cells (HCT116) and melanoma cells (B16F10) using an MTT (3-(4,5-dimethylthiazol-2-yl)-2,5-diphenyltetrazolium bromide) assay. A methanolic crude extract of eggs was obtained by cold maceration, followed by fractionation to obtain hexane, chloroform, ethyl acetate, n-butanol, and aqueous fractions. The methanolic crude extract decreased cell viability of HCT-116 and B16F10 cell lines at higher concentrations. The other fractions were evaluated using a cell viability assay, and chloroform and hexane showed the highest activity at significantly lower concentrations than did the methanolic fraction. Full scan profiles of the methanolic crude extract and the chloroform and hexane fractions were obtained by gas chromatography mass spectrometry (GC-MS), and the resultant compounds were identified by comparing their spectral data to those available in spectral matching libraries. ROS generation assay, flow cytometry, and western blot analysis provided supporting evidence that the hexane and chloroform fractions induced cell death in HCT116 and B16-F10 cell lines. All fractions were further tested for antibacterial activity against <i>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</i>, among which the hexane fraction showed the highest zone of inhibition on LB nutrient agar plates. This study demonstrated promising anticancer and antibacterial effects of <i>Artemia salina</i> egg extracts. Our results suggest that pure bioactive compounds obtained from <i>Artemia salina</i> eggs can provide new insights into the mechanisms of colon and skin cancer, as well as <i>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</i> inhibition.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Islam</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Salman Ul</ForeName>
                    <Initials>SU</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, College of Natural Sciences, Kyungpook National University, 41566, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Ahmed</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Muhammad Bilal</ForeName>
                    <Initials>MB</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, College of Natural Sciences, Kyungpook National University, 41566, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Shehzad</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Adeeb</ForeName>
                    <Initials>A</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Pharmacy, Institute for Research and Medical Consultations (IRMC), Imam Abdurahman Bin Faisal University, Dammam, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Lee</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Young Sup</ForeName>
                    <Initials>YS</Initials>
                    <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5841-6506</Identifier>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, College of Natural Sciences, Kyungpook National University, 41566, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>06</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Evid Based Complement Alternat Med</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101215021</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>1741-427X</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>01</Month>
                <Day>18</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>04</Month>
                <Day>10</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>04</Month>
                <Day>22</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198432</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/9528256</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6526577</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

