


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198431</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">1741-427X</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>2019</Volume>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Evidence-based complementary and alternative medicine : eCAM</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Evid Based Complement Alternat Med</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Medicinal Properties and Active Constituents of <i>Dracocephalum kotschyi</i> and Its Significance in Iran: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>9465309</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2019/9465309</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="Objectives" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED"><i>Dracocephalum</i> has over 60 species and is found mainly in the temperate regions of Asia and Europe. One of these species, <i>i.e., Dracocephalum kotschyi</i> Boiss, is known to have a number of medicinal properties and active ingredients in many parts of the world. Despite being an endemic wild-flowering plant of great importance, the plant is currently considered endangered in Iran. Besides, there is paucity of information on the significance of the medicinal properties and active constituents of <i>D. kotschyi</i> among the Iranian people. On that account a systematic review of studies reporting on the medicinal properties and active ingredients and its significance to human and animal health was conducted and the existing knowledge gaps were identified.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Methods" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines were used in the search for published articles on medicinal properties and active ingredients of <i>D. kotschyi</i> and its significance on humans and animals in Iran. The search was confined to scientific articles from repositories of popular data bases and search engines among them PubMed, Web of Science, Google Scholar, Science Direct, SpringerLink, and Scopus. The search narrowed down on scientific journals, books, and book chapters focusing on the medicinal properties of <i>D. kotschyi</i> in Iran for the period between 1970 and 2018.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Results" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 1158 scientific articles were sourced from the various databases, out of which 38 met the search criteria and qualified for this review. The studies were conducted in only 9 of the 31 provinces of Iran, with a large proportion in Isfahan province, central Iran. The studies showed that all plant parts (roots, aerial parts, flowers, and leaves) had active constituents. Essential oils and aerial plant parts were the main components studied. Nevertheless, the most frequently reported constituents were xanthomicrol, limonene, luteolin, geranial, apigenin, and calycopterin. A number of medicinal properties were reported among them antioxidant, antibacterial, anticancerous, antinociceptive, antihyperlipidemic, antispasmodic, cytotoxic, and immunomodulatory effects. The plant was also reported to be a remedy for inflammatory pain, headaches, congestion, liver disorders, ulcer, fever, renal pain, dyspepsia, stomach ache, abdominal pain, joints pains, muscle spasm, congestion, bloating, and wound healing effects, among others.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Conclusion" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This review has shown that <i>D. kotschyi</i> is an important medicinal plant with a large number of active constituents and great potential to safeguard human and animal health in Iran. However, over utilization of the <i>D. kotschyi</i> plant is already endangering its existence. Nevertheless, more studies need be conducted across the country.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Heydari</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Parisa</ForeName>
                    <Initials>P</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Persian Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Traditional Medicine, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Yavari</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Maryam</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Persian Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Traditional Medicine, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Adibi</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Peyman</ForeName>
                    <Initials>P</Initials>
                    <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3247-4828</Identifier>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Integrative Functional Gastroenterology Research Center, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Asghari</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Gholamreza</ForeName>
                    <Initials>G</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacognosy, School of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Sciences, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Ghanadian</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Syed-Mustafa</ForeName>
                    <Initials>SM</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacognosy, Faculty of Pharmacy, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Dida</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Gabriel O</ForeName>
                    <Initials>GO</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>School of Public Health and Community Development, Maseno University, Kenya.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Community and Public Health, Technical University of Kenya, Nairobi, Kenya.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Khamesipour</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Faham</ForeName>
                    <Initials>F</Initials>
                    <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0678-2528</Identifier>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Cellular and Molecular Research Center, Sabzevar University of Medical Sciences, Sabzevar, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>06</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Evid Based Complement Alternat Med</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101215021</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>1741-427X</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2018</Year>
                <Month>09</Month>
                <Day>24</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2018</Year>
                <Month>11</Month>
                <Day>25</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>02</Month>
                <Day>04</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198431</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/9465309</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6526565</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

