


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198402</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">1314-2011</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>123</Volume>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>PhytoKeys</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>PhytoKeys</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>A revision of the Morelloid Clade of <i>Solanum</i> L. (Solanaceae) in North and Central America and the Caribbean.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>1-144</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3897/phytokeys.123.31738</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>The Morelloid Clade, also known as the black nightshades or &quot;Maurella&quot; (Morella), is one of the 10 major clades within the mega-diverse genus <i>Solanum</i> L. The clade is most species rich in the central to southern Andes, but species occur around the tropics and subtropics, some extending well into the temperate zone. Plants of the group are herbaceous or short-lived perennials, with small white or purplish white flowers, and small juicy berries. Due to the complex morphological variation and weedy nature of these plants, coupled with the large number of published synonyms (especially for European taxa), our understanding of species limits and diversity in the Morelloid Clade has lagged behind that of other major groups in <i>Solanum</i>. Here we provide the second in a three-part series of revisions of the morelloid solanums treating the species occurring in North and Central America and the Caribbean (for the Old World see &quot;PhytoKeys 106&quot;, the third part will treat species of South America). Synonymy, morphological descriptions, distribution maps, and common names and uses are provided for all 18 species occurring in this region. We treat 10 of these species as native, and eight as putatively naturalised, introduced and/or invasive in the region. We provide complete descriptions with nomenclatural details, including lecto- and neotypifications, for all species. Keys to all species occurring in the whole region and for each area within it (i.e., North America, Central America and Mexico, and the islands of the Caribbean), illustrations to aid identification both in herbaria and in the field, and distribution maps are provided. Preliminary conservation assessments are provided for all species. Details of all specimens examined are provided in three Supplementary materials sections.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Knapp</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Sandra</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Life Sciences, Natural History Museum, Cromwell Road, London SW7 5BD, UK Natural History Museum London United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Barboza</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Gloria E</ForeName>
                    <Initials>GE</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Instituto Multidisciplinario de Biología Vegetal (CONICET-Universidad Nacional de Córdoba), Casilla de Correo 495, 5000 Córdoba, Argentina Instituto Multidisciplinario de Biología Vegetal Córdoba Argentina.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Bohs</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Lynn</ForeName>
                    <Initials>L</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Biology, 1400 South, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA University of Utah Salt Lake City United States of America.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Särkinen</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Tiina</ForeName>
                    <Initials>T</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh, 20A Inverleith Row, Edinburgh EH3 5LR, UK Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Edinburgh United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>30</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Bulgaria</Country>
            <MedlineTA>PhytoKeys</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101548554</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>1314-2003</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N"> Solanum </Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antilles</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Caribbean</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Central America</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mexico</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">North America</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">black nightshades</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vegetables</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">weeds</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2018</Year>
                <Month>11</Month>
                <Day>18</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>04</Month>
                <Day>03</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198402</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3897/phytokeys.123.31738</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">31738</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6554266</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

