


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198346</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0976-4879</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>11</Volume>
                    <Issue>Suppl 2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>May</Month>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Journal of pharmacy &amp; bioallied sciences</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>J Pharm Bioallied Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Efficacy of Three Types of Plaque Control Methods During Fixed Orthodontic Treatment: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>S246-S251</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/JPBS.JPBS_1_19</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="Aim" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The aim of this study was to evaluate and compare the efficacy of three types of plaque control methods among 13- to 35-year-old subjects receiving fixed orthodontic treatment in Coorg Institute of Dental Sciences, Virajpet, Coorg district, Karnataka, India.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Materials and Methods" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 111 subjects who fulfilled the inclusion and exclusion criteria were randomly included in the study. The subjects were recalled after 1 month of the commencement of fixed orthodontic treatment for the recording of baseline data including plaque index (PI), gingival index (GI), and modified papillary bleeding index (MPBI). After recording of the baseline data, the subjects were randomly allocated into each of the intervention groups, i.e., group A (manual tooth brush), group B (powered tooth brush), and group C (manual tooth brush combined with mouthwash) by lottery method. Further, all the subjects were recalled after 1 and 2 months for recording the data.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Results" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Regarding plaque levels, it was seen that there was a highly statistically significant difference between the three groups (<i>P</i> = 0.001), with the manual tooth brush combined with chlorhexidine mouthwash group recording the lowest mean PI score of 0.5 ± 0.39. A comparison of the mean GI scores among the groups at the end of 2 months shows a highly statistically significant difference (<i>P</i> = 0.001). The mean MPBI scores at the end of 2 months were highly statistically significant among the three groups (<i>P</i> = 0.001), with the group C recording the lowest mean MPBI score of 0.3 ± 0.3.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Conclusion" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The powered tooth brush group subjects exhibited significantly lesser PI, GI, and MPBI scores than the manual tooth brush group at the end of 2 months, whereas the manual tooth brush combined with chlorhexidine mouth wash group subjects showed maximum improvement, having significantly lesser PI and GI scores than the powered tooth brush group.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Shilpa</LastName>
                    <ForeName>M</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Public Health Dentistry, A B Shetty Memorial Institute of Dental Sciences, NITTE (Deemed to be University), Deralakatte, Mangaluru, India.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Jain</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Jithesh</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Public Health Dentistry, Coorg Institute of Dental Sciences, Virajpet, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Shahid</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Fazal</ForeName>
                    <Initials>F</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Orthodontic Unit, School of Dental Science, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Gufran</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Khalid</ForeName>
                    <Initials>K</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Division of Periodontics, Department of Preventive Dental Sciences, College of Dentistry, Prince Sattam bin Abdul Aziz University, Alkharj, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Sam</LastName>
                    <ForeName>George</ForeName>
                    <Initials>G</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Division of Orthodontics, Department of Preventive Dental Sciences, College of Dentistry, Prince Sattam bin Abdul Aziz University, Alkharj, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Khan</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Mohammed S</ForeName>
                    <Initials>MS</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Division of Periodontics, Department of Preventive Dental Sciences, College of Dentistry, Prince Sattam bin Abdul Aziz University, Alkharj, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>India</Country>
            <MedlineTA>J Pharm Bioallied Sci</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101537209</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0975-7406</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fixed orthodontic treatment</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral hygiene</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plaque</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">toothbrush</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
        <CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198346</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/JPBS.JPBS_1_19</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">JPBS-11-246</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6555356</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

