


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198239</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0259-1162</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>13</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <MedlineDate>2019 Apr-Jun</MedlineDate>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Anesthesia, essays and researches</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Anesth Essays Res</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Efficacy of Stroke Volume Variation, Cardiac Output and Cardiac Index as Predictors of Fluid Responsiveness using Minimally Invasive Vigileo Device in Intracranial Surgeries.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>248-253</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/aer.AER_10_19</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="Introduction" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Functional hemodynamic monitoring using dynamic parameters such as stroke volume variations (SVVs) based on pulse contour analysis is considered more accurate than central venous pressure and mean arterial pressure (MAP) in predicting fluid responsiveness. New device, i.e., Vigileo system, allows automatic and continuous monitoring of cardiac output (CO) based on pulse contour analysis and respiratory stroke volume.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Aim" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The study aims to test the above hypothesis using graded volume loading step (VLS) to assess the accuracy of SVV as a predictor of fluid responsiveness in patients undergoing intracranial surgery.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Materials and Methods" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">After taking ethical committee approval and informed consent, 60 patients aged between 18 and 55 years belonging to the American Society of Anesthesiologists physical status Class I and II, of either sex, scheduled for brain surgery were included in the study. In this study, 5 min after intubation, with stable hemodynamics, patients received volume loading in successive steps (VLS) of 200 ml of lactated Ringer's solution until the stroke volume increased to &lt;10%. Blood pressure (BP), heart rate (HR), stroke volume (SV), and SVV were measured before and after each VLS. Optimal preload augmentation required by each patient was measured by the number of VLS after which an increase in SV was &lt;10%.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Results" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There was a significant decrease in the baseline BP and SV in responsive and nonresponsive groups for the first VLS, but there is no change in HR statistically. There was a significant change in SV after first VLS. Receiver operating characteristic analysis showed a larger area under the curve of 0.758 for SVV compared to other measured variables. The median number of VLS administered were 2 per patient equating to a mean ± SD requirement of 368 ± 176 ml of crystalloid per patient as the optimal preoperative infusion volume.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="Conclusion" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">SVV is a better predictor of preload responsiveness measured with third-generation Vigileo device when compared to BP and HR.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Shaik</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Zareena</ForeName>
                    <Initials>Z</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesiology, Siddhartha Medical College, Vijayawada, Andhra Pradesh, India.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Mulam</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Santhi Sree</ForeName>
                    <Initials>SS</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesiology, Siddhartha Medical College, Vijayawada, Andhra Pradesh, India.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>India</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Anesth Essays Res</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101578762</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>2229-7685</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurosurgeries</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vigileo device</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stroke volume variation</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">volume loading steps</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
        <CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198239</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/aer.AER_10_19</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">AER-13-248</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6545965</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

