


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198217</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0042-4668</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>84</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Vestnik otorinolaringologii</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Vestn. Otorinolaringol.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[Features of microsurgery of the vestibular larynx using CO and a diode laser].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>57-60</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17116/otorino20198402157</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>The purpose of the study was to evaluate the possibility of using and the effectiveness of CO<sub>2</sub> and diode lasers in the microsurgery of the vestibular larynx. 85 surgical interventions were performed (using CO<sub>2</sub> laser - 45, diode - 40) on the vestibular larynx of 52 patients (papillomatosis, cicatricial stenosis, cysts, hyperplastic laryngitis, initial stage of laryngeal cancer). The complications, duration of the intervention and inflammatory changes after the operation were assessed. In 3 (3.5%) cases, the use of CO<sub>2</sub> laser was complicated by bleeding. The duration of the intervention with the use of a CO<sub>2</sub> laser averaged 24±5.6 minutes, with a diode laser 30±5.4 minutes (p&lt;0.05). In patients with a diode laser, edema, mucosal congestion, fibrin and pain were significantly longer than patients after using a CO<sub>2</sub> laser (p&lt;0.05). Thus, the use of CO<sub>2</sub> laser in the surgical treatment of the vestibular laryngeal region occurs with less time, a less prolonged inflammatory response, but in some cases requires additional methods of hemostasis.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Vavin</LastName>
                    <ForeName>V V</ForeName>
                    <Initials>VV</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>State autonomous public health institution 'Kemerovo Regional Clinical Hospital', Kemerovo, Russia, 650066.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Dobretsov</LastName>
                    <ForeName>K G</ForeName>
                    <Initials>KG</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Center for Otorhinolaryngology, Federal Siberian Scientific and Clinical Center of FMBA of Russia, Krasnoyarsk, Russia, 660035.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>rus</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Osobennosti mikrokhirurgii vestibuliarnogo otdela gortani s ispol'zovaniem SO2-lazera i diodnogo lazera.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Russia (Federation)</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Vestn Otorinolaringol</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0416577</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0042-4668</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="rus">
            <AbstractText>Цель исследования - оценить возможность применения и эффективность СО<sub>2</sub>- и диодного лазеров в микрохирургии вестибулярного отдела гортани. Проведено 85 оперативных вмешательств (с применением СО<sub>2</sub>-лазера - 45, диодного лазера - 40) на вестибулярном отделе гортани у 52 пациентов (диагнозы: папилломатоз, рубцовый стеноз, кисты, гиперпластический ларингит, начальная стадия рака гортани). Оценены осложнения, длительность проводимого вмешательства и воспалительных изменений после операции. В 3 (3,5%) случаях использование СО<sub>2</sub>-лазера осложнилось кровотечением. Длительность вмешательства при использовании СО<sub>2</sub>-лазера составила в среднем 24±5,6 мин, при использовании диодного лазера - 30±5,4 мин (p&lt;0,05). У пациентов с использованием диодного лазера отек, гиперемия слизистой оболочки, наличие фибрина и болевого синдрома имели значимо большую продолжительность по сравнению с пациентами после использования СО<sub>2</sub>-лазера (p&lt;0,05). Таким образом, использование СО<sub>2</sub>-лазера при хирургическом лечении вестибулярного отдела гортани проходит с меньшими временны`ми затратами, менее продолжительной воспалительной реакцией, но в ряде случаев требует дополнительных методов гемостаза.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CO2 laser</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complications</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diode laser</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microsurgery</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vestibular larynx</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198217</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17116/otorino20198402157</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

