


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198214</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0042-4668</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>84</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Vestnik otorinolaringologii</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Vestn. Otorinolaringol.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[Functional activity of neutrophils and local manifestations of oxidative stress in the mucous membrane of the nasal cavity in the early postoperative period].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>40-45</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17116/otorino20198402140</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>The purpose of the study was to study the factors of antimicrobial, antioxidant defense, variability of nasal secretion lipid peroxidation in patients with curvature of the nasal septum in the early postoperative period. METHODS: microbiological, immunological (assessment of the activity and intensity of phagocytosis, nitrous tetrazolium reduction test) biochemical (study of content diene conjugates, ketodienes, conjugated trines and Schiff bases in the lipid extract of neutrophilic granulocytes), statistical. RESULTS: The dynamics of the content, functional and biochemical activity of neutrophilic granulocytes in nasal washings in individuals who underwent rhinosurgical intervention testifies to the presence of qualitative and quantitative changes in neutrophilic granulocytes of the nasal secretion, recorded in reactions of oxygen-dependent metabolism, free radical oxidation and antioxidant protection.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Gizinger</LastName>
                    <ForeName>O A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>OA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>South Ural State Medical University, Department of Microbiology, Virology, Immunology and Clinical Diagnostics Department of South Ural State Medical University, Chelyabinsk, Russia, 454092.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Korkmazov</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A M</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AM</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>South Ural State Medical University, Department of otorhinolaryngology of South Ural State Medical University, Chelyabinsk, Russia, 454092.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Sumerkina</LastName>
                    <ForeName>V A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>VA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>South Ural State Medical University, Department of Microbiology, Virology, Immunology and Clinical Diagnostics Department of South Ural State Medical University, Chelyabinsk, Russia, 454092.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>rus</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Funktsional'naia aktivnost' neĭtrofilov i lokal'nye proiavleniia okislitel'nogo stressa v slizistoĭ obolochke polosti nosa v rannem posleoperatsionnom periode.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Russia (Federation)</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Vestn Otorinolaringol</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0416577</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0042-4668</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="rus">
            <AbstractText>Цель работы - изучение факторов антимикробной, антиоксидантной защиты, вариабельности процессов липопероксидации назального секрета у больных с искривлением носовой перегородки в раннем послеоперационном периоде. Материал и методы. Микробиологические, иммунологические (оценка активности и интенсивности фагоцитоза, тест восстановления нитросинего тетразолия), биохимические (исследование интенсивности липопероксидации по уровню первичных, вторичных и конечных продуктов перекисного окисления липидов: диеновых конъюгатов, кетодиенов и сопряженных триенов, оснований Шиффа в липидном экстракте), статистические. Результаты - динамика содержания, функциональной и биохимической активности нейтрофильных гранулоцитов в назальных смывах у лиц, перенесших ринохирургическое вмешательство, свидетельствует о наличии качественных и количественных изменений нейтрофильных гранулоцитов назального секрета, регистрируемых в реакциях кислород-зависимого метаболизма, свободнорадикального окисления и антиоксидантной защиты.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antioxidant protection</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">innate immunity</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nasal septum</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rhinoseptoplasty</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198214</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17116/otorino20198402140</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

