


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198212</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0042-4668</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>84</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Vestnik otorinolaringologii</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Vestn. Otorinolaringol.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[Sequential bilateral cochlear implantation with long interval between surgeries in deaf-blind patient].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>29-35</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17116/otorino20198402129</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>The efficacy of sequential bilateral cochlear implantation with long interval between surgeries (18 years) was investigated in deaf-blind patient (22 years old man, lost hearing and vision after meningitis at the age 2.5 years). At the age 4 years he got cochlear implant at right ear. His speech skills completely disappeared before the implantation. Auditory-speech rehabilitation with cochlear implant was successful - patient has good auditory, language, speech, cognitive skills. At the age 22 years patient made decision to get cochlear implant at the left ear after breakdown of internal part of cochlear implant at right ear in spite of successful reoperation. After activation of new processor (all electrodes were activated) the patient got daily auditory training with cochlear implant at left ear (Concerto/Opus 2, Medel) on the base of 'auditory' method, in daily life patient uses 2 devices. After 1 month of using cochlear implant at left ear the patient recognized environmental sounds and music instruments, words and sentences in close set tests EARS battery, the score for OLSA test in quiet was 90%, but the perception in noise was complicated. The balance of parameters of fitting for 1-st and 2-nd processors and special auditory training with two cochlear implants provided the development of initial binaural interaction. Perilinqually deaf patients can achieve high effect after sequential bilateral cochlear implantation with long interval between surgeries. The necessary conditions are - preservation of electrical activity of auditory nerve, intensive structured auditory training with new 'ear', patient's motivation of using of cochlear implant at 'new' ear.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Koroleva</LastName>
                    <ForeName>I V</ForeName>
                    <Initials>IV</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>St.-Petersburg scientific research Institute of ear, throat, nose and speech, Bronnitskaya 9, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Kusovkov</LastName>
                    <ForeName>V E</ForeName>
                    <Initials>VE</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>St.-Petersburg scientific research Institute of ear, throat, nose and speech, Bronnitskaya 9, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Levin</LastName>
                    <ForeName>S V</ForeName>
                    <Initials>SV</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>St.-Petersburg scientific research Institute of ear, throat, nose and speech, Bronnitskaya 9, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Ogorodnikova</LastName>
                    <ForeName>E A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>EA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Pavlov Institute of Physiology RAS, nab. Makarova 6, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 199034.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Yanov</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Yu K</ForeName>
                    <Initials>YK</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>St.-Petersburg scientific research Institute of ear, throat, nose and speech, Bronnitskaya 9, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Astashchenko</LastName>
                    <ForeName>S V</ForeName>
                    <Initials>SV</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>St.-Petersburg scientific research Institute of ear, throat, nose and speech, Bronnitskaya 9, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>rus</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Posledovatel'naia bilateral'naia kokhlearnaia implantatsiia s dlitel'nym intervalom mezhdu operatsiiami u slepoglukhogo patsienta.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Russia (Federation)</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Vestn Otorinolaringol</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0416577</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0042-4668</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="rus">
            <AbstractText>Исследовалась эффективность последовательной билатеральной кохлеарной имплантации (КИ) с длительным интервалом между операциями (18 лет) у рано оглохшего слепоглухого пациента (22 года, потеря слуха и зрения в 2,5 года после менингоэнцефалита). Пациент не использовал слуховые аппараты из-за отсутствия эффекта, в 4 года ему была проведена КИ на правом ухе. На момент операции у ребенка полностью распалась речь. С кохлеарным имплантом у пациента сформировались слухоречевое восприятие и устная речь. В 22 года после поломки импланта, несмотря на успешную реоперацию, пациент решился провести КИ на левом ухе. С пациентом проводилась ежедневная слухоречевая тренировка при включенном процессоре только на левом ухе (Concerto/Opus 2, Medel) с применением 'слухового' метода, в течение дня он использовал оба процессора. Через 1 мес после первого включения нового процессора (активированы все электроды) пациент успешно узнавал с его помощью окружающие и музыкальные звуки, речевые сигналы, выполнял Ольденбургский фразовый тест в тишине (90% правильных слов), но испытывал трудности при восприятии теста в шуме. Согласование параметров настройки 2 процессоров и специальные занятия способствовали появлению начальных навыков бинаурального взаимодействия. Таким образом, у рано оглохших пациентов может быть достигнут высокий эффект при последовательной билатеральной КИ с длительным интервалом между двумя операциями. Необходимые условия этого - сохранность электрической активности слухового нерва, организация интенсивной структурированной слухоречевой тренировки, мотивация пациента к использованию импланта на втором ухе.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">auditory rehabilitation</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cochlear implants</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deafness</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sequential bilateral cochlear implantation</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198212</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17116/otorino20198402129</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

