


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198211</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0042-4668</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>84</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Vestnik otorinolaringologii</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Vestn. Otorinolaringol.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[Single-stage open tympanoplasty in the form of tympanosclerosis with fixation of the stapes].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>23-28</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17116/otorino20198402123</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>We used several variants of one-stage tympanoplasty, including our own method, according to which, in the absence of an anvil and malleus after mobilisation of the stapes, ossiculoplasty with partial or complete ossicular prosthesis and myringoplasty simultaneously preventively created a support (neo-malleus) in the thickness of the neotympanic membrane. To assess the effectiveness of different variants of single-stage tympanoplasty, the long-term functional results were compared in terms of 6 to 12 months after the intervention with preoperative indicators. Standard methods of statistical estimation with calculation of descriptive statistics and methods of statistical hypothesis testing based on nonparametric Wilcoxon criterion for related samples were used. All the variants of one-stage tympanoplasty used in the fixation of the stapes are effective and, in general, make it possible to achieve an improvement in auditory function. In the present study, this result was achieved in 61 of 86 patients with tympanosclerosis (71% (65%; 74%) of 95% CI). The functional results of tympanoplasty according to the developed method do not differ from the results of traditional variants with the use of prostheses, but the implementation of this variant of tympanoplasty in the absence of an anvil and hammer allows for the fixation of the stapes during the reoperative stapedotomy using a prosthesis of the piston type without additional surgical stage of the formation of the neomaleus.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Chernushevich</LastName>
                    <ForeName>I I</ForeName>
                    <Initials>II</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>St.-Petersburg scientific research Institute of ear, throat, nose and speech, Bronnitskaya 9, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Anikin</LastName>
                    <ForeName>I A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>IA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>St.-Petersburg scientific research Institute of ear, throat, nose and speech, Bronnitskaya 9, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Agazaryan</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A G</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AG</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>St.-Petersburg scientific research Institute of ear, throat, nose and speech, Bronnitskaya 9, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Korneyenkov</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>St.-Petersburg scientific research Institute of ear, throat, nose and speech, Bronnitskaya 9, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Zakharova</LastName>
                    <ForeName>G P</ForeName>
                    <Initials>GP</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>St.-Petersburg scientific research Institute of ear, throat, nose and speech, Bronnitskaya 9, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Astashchenko</LastName>
                    <ForeName>S V</ForeName>
                    <Initials>SV</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>St.-Petersburg scientific research Institute of ear, throat, nose and speech, Bronnitskaya 9, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>rus</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Odnoétapnaia timpanoplastika pri otkrytoĭ forme timpanoskleroza s fiksatsieĭ stremeni.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Russia (Federation)</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Vestn Otorinolaringol</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0416577</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0042-4668</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="rus">
            <AbstractText>В работе использовали несколько вариантов одноэтапной тимпанопластики, в том числе собственный способ, согласно которому при отсутствии наковальни и молоточка после мобилизации стремени, оссикулопластики частичным или полным оссикулярным протезом и мирингопластики одномоментно профилактически создавали опору (неомаллеус) в толще неотимпанальной мембраны. Для оценки эффективности различных вариантов одноэтапной тимпанопластики сравнивали отдаленные функциональные результаты в сроки 6-12 мес после вмешательства с дооперационными показателями. Использовали стандартные методы статистического оценивания с расчетом описательных статистик и методы проверки статистических гипотез на основе непараметрического критерия Вилкоксона для связанных выборок. Все использованные в работе варианты одноэтапной тимпанопластики при фиксации стремени эффективны и в целом позволяют добиться улучшения слуховой функции. В настоящем исследовании такой результат был достигнут у 61 из 86 больных тимпаносклерозом (71% (65%; 74%) 95% ДИ). Функциональные результаты тимпанопластики по разработанному способу практически не отличаются от результатов традиционных вариантов с использованием протезов, но выполнение этого варианта тимпанопластики в случае отсутствия наковальни и молоточка позволяет при рефиксации стремени осуществить в ходе реоперации стапедотомию с использованием протеза типа 'пистон' без дополнительного хирургического этапа формирования неомаллеуса.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fixation of the stapes</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ossiculoplasty</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tympanoplasty</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tympanosclerosis</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198211</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17116/otorino20198402123</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

