


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198210</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0042-4668</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>84</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Vestnik otorinolaringologii</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Vestn. Otorinolaringol.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[Preoperative screening for the hemostatic system in ENT surgery in children].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>18-22</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17116/otorino20198402118</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>The analysis (1998-2018) of the causes of early postoperative bleeding in 68 children with chronic lymphoproliferative syndrome and late postoperative bleeding (on the 7-10th day) in 3 children aged 3 to 17 years was performed. It was found the disorder of the platelet functional activity (adrenaline-induced platelet aggregation, adrenaline concentration - 2.5 µmol/l) in 83.8% cases (57 children). Late postoperative bleedings were developed due to the uncontrolled intake of nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory painkillers, which led to the platelet dysfunction. It has been established the decrease in the prothrombin percent by Quick in 73.5% children, and the elongation of the activated partial thromboplastin time (APTT) in the quarter of children amid the bleeding. Half of the children showed the increase of D-dimer concentration to 1.5-2 fold amid the bleeding. We offer preoperative examination: platelet count, prothrombin percent by Quick (prothrombin time), APTT and fibrinogen level. We recommend an extended hemostasis study with the detection of adhesive, aggregative and secretory functions of platelets in the children with chronic lymphoproliferative syndrome if the results of the integral screening tests differ from normal range.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Drozdova</LastName>
                    <ForeName>M V</ForeName>
                    <Initials>MV</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Saint-Petersburg Research Institute of Ear, Throat, Nose and Speech, Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Maltzeva</LastName>
                    <ForeName>G S</ForeName>
                    <Initials>GS</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Saint-Petersburg Research Institute of Ear, Throat, Nose and Speech, Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Tyrnova</LastName>
                    <ForeName>E V</ForeName>
                    <Initials>EV</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Saint-Petersburg Research Institute of Ear, Throat, Nose and Speech, Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, St.-Petersburg, Russia, 190013.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>rus</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Predoperatsionnyĭ skrining sistemy gemostaza pri operatsiiakh na LOR-organakh u deteĭ.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Russia (Federation)</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Vestn Otorinolaringol</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0416577</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0042-4668</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="rus">
            <AbstractText>Проведен анализ (1998-2018 гг.) причин развития ранних послеоперационных кровотечений у 68 детей с хроническим лимфопролиферативным синдромом в возрасте от 3 до 17 лет, поздних послеоперационных кровотечений (на 7-10-й день) у 3 детей. В 83,8% случаев (57 детей) наблюдали нарушение функциональной активности тромбоцитов (адреналин-индуцированная агрегация тромбоцитов, концентрация 2,5 мкмоль/л). Поздние послеоперационные кровотечения развились на фоне неконтролируемого приема обезболивающих нестероидных противовоспалительных препаратов, что привело к нарушению функции тромбоцитов. На фоне кровотечения отмечено снижение процента протромбина по Квику у 73,5% детей, у четверти детей - удлинение АЧТВ. У половины детей отмечено повышение концентрации D-димера в 1,5-2 раза. Предлагаем проводить предоперационное обследование: количество тромбоцитов, процент протромбина по Квику, АЧТВ, фибриноген. При выявлении отклонений результатов интегральных тестов скрининга рекомендуем расширенное гемостазиологическое исследование с определением адгезивной, агрегационной и секреторной функций тромбоцитов.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adenotonsillectomy</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">child</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic lymphoproliferative syndrome</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">platelet aggregation</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postoperative bleeding</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198210</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17116/otorino20198402118</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

