


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198208</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0042-4668</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>84</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Vestnik otorinolaringologii</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Vestn. Otorinolaringol.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[Medical and social rehabilitation of hearing impairment from occupational noise].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>8-12</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17116/otorino2019840218</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>The article presents the main provisions of medical and social rehabilitation of various hearing disorders caused by industrial noise. Two forms of hearing organ pathology in accordance with ICD-10 are distinguished: 'Adverse effects of industrial noise' - Z57.0 and 'hearing Loss caused by noise' - H83.3. The main methods of drug and non-drug rehabilitation of patients with signs of adverse effects of noise on the hearing organ and medical and social bases of rehabilitation of patients with severe clinical forms of hearing loss from noise are revealed. The basic principles of medical and social expertise in professional hearing loss: determination of the date of establishment and degree of loss of professional capacity for work, the need of the victim in medical, social and professional rehabilitation, recognition of the victim as a disabled person due to occupational disease, the development of the rehabilitation program of the victim in the workplace. References to the main Federal and industry documents of the Ministry of labor and the Ministry of health regulating medical and social rehabilitation are given.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Pankova</LastName>
                    <ForeName>V B</ForeName>
                    <Initials>VB</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Federal state unitary enterprise 'all-Russian research Institute of railway hygiene' Rospotrebnadzor, Moscow, Russia, 125497.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Letskaya</LastName>
                    <ForeName>O A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>OA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Federal state institution 'The Main Bureau of medical and social examination in Moscow of the Ministry of labour and social protection of the Russian Federation', Moscow, Russia, 125040.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>rus</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Meditsinskaia i sotsial'naia reabilitatsiia lits s narusheniiami slukha ot proizvodstvennogo shuma.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Russia (Federation)</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Vestn Otorinolaringol</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0416577</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0042-4668</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="rus">
            <AbstractText>В статье представлены основные положения медицинской и социальной реабилитации лиц с различными нарушениями слуха, вызванными производственным шумом. Выделены две формы патологии органа слуха в соответствии с МКБ-10: 'Неблагоприятное воздействие производственного шума' - Z57.0 и 'Потеря слуха, вызванная шумом' - H83.3. Раскрыты основные приемы медикаментозной и немедикаментозной реабилитации пациентов с признаками неблагоприятного воздействия шума на орган слуха и медико-социальные основы реабилитации больных с выраженными клиническими формами потери слуха от шума. Обсуждены основные принципы медико-социальной экспертизы при профессиональной тугоухости: определение даты установления и степени утраты профессиональной трудоспособности, нуждаемость пострадавшего в медицинской, социальной и профессиональной реабилитации, признание пострадавшего инвалидом в связи с профессиональным заболеванием, разработка программы реабилитации пострадавшего на производстве. Даны ссылки на основные Федеральные и отраслевые документы Минтруда и Минздрава, регламентирующие медико-социальную реабилитацию.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic sensorineural hearing loss</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disability</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hearing aid</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hearing loss from noise</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">occupational disease of the hearing organ</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical methods of influence</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social rehabilitation</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198208</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17116/otorino2019840218</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

