


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198201</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0039-4521</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>62</Volume>
                    <Issue>3</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Sudebno-meditsinskaia ekspertiza</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Sud. Med. Ekspert.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[Morphogenesis of central and peripheral liver ruptures in blunt-force trauma].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>28-32</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17116/sudmed20196203128</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>The purpose of this study was an in depth investigation of the morphogenesis of central and peripheral liver ruptures in blunt trauma and to obtain additional information about their forensic medical significance. It has been established that central and peripheral ruptures are formed by shocks caused by very high forces, as well as by frontal compression of the body as a result of general deformation of the organ and rupture of parenchyma from stretching and tissue shearing. The surface relief of central ruptures was found to be independent of the type of external influence and was determined by the size of the rupture. The peripheral part of such ruptures was characterized by a relatively homogeneous surface topography formed by shear ridges, while the central part was characterized by an inhomogeneous surface topography formed by tensile zones. The surface relief of peripheral ruptures also did not depend on the type of external influence. The surface was relatively homogeneous, with ridges along the edge of the rupture, shear ridges and stretch zones directed deep into the rupture and forming the rupture surface relief in the form of alternating elevations and depressions.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Dubrovina</LastName>
                    <ForeName>I A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>IA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine of the Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University under Ministry of Health of the Russia, Moscow, Russia, 119991.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Dubrovin</LastName>
                    <ForeName>I A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>IA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine of the Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University under Ministry of Health of the Russia, Moscow, Russia, 119991.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Bychkov</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine of the Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University under Ministry of Health of the Russia, Moscow, Russia, 119991.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Aulov</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine of the Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University under Ministry of Health of the Russia, Moscow, Russia, 119991.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Grukhovskiy</LastName>
                    <ForeName>S V</ForeName>
                    <Initials>SV</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine of the Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University under Ministry of Health of the Russia, Moscow, Russia, 119991.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Mosoyan</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A S</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AS</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine and Law of the Pavlov First St. Petersburg State Medical University of the Ministry of Healthcare of Russian Federation, St. Petersburg, Russia, 197022.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>rus</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Morfogenez tsentral'nykh i perifericheskikh razryvov pecheni pri travme tupymi predmetami.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Russia (Federation)</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Sud Med Ekspert</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0404546</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0039-4521</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="rus">
            <AbstractText>Цель исследования - углубленное изучение морфогенеза центральных и периферических разрывов печени при тупой травме и получение дополнительной информации об их судебно-медицинском значении. Установили, что центральные и периферические разрывы образуются при ударных воздействиях, причиненных с очень большой силой, а также при фронтальной компрессии тела в результате общей деформации органа и разрыва паренхимы от растяжения и сдвига ткани. Рельеф поверхности центральных разрывов не зависит от вида внешнего воздействия и определяется размером разрыва. Периферическая часть таких разрывов характеризуется относительно однородным рельефом поверхности, сформированным гребнями сдвига, центральная часть - неоднородным рельефом поверхности, сформированным зонами растяжения. Рельеф поверхности периферических разрывов также не зависит от вида внешнего воздействия. Характерна относительно однородная поверхность, образованная гребнями отрыва, расположенными вдоль края разрыва, гребнями сдвига и зонами растяжения, направленными в глубь разрыва и формирующими рельеф поверхности разрыва в виде чередующихся возвышений и углублений.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blunt trauma</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">forensic medical assessment</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">relief of liver rupture surface</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198201</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17116/sudmed20196203128</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

