


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198200</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0039-4521</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>62</Volume>
                    <Issue>3</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Sudebno-meditsinskaia ekspertiza</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Sud. Med. Ekspert.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[General characteristics of morphometric and morphoscopic signs of liver rupture with different localizations].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>21-27</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17116/sudmed20196203121</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>The aim of this study was to compare the morphoscopic and morphometric features of local and remote liver ruptures under various external influences. It was found that the local main ruptures were formed in the case of impact trauma more often in the right side of the liver on its diaphragmatic surface, in the anterior third of the organ. They were linear and located in the longitudinal direction. The size of the ruptures increased as the impact force increased. Local additional ruptures were associated with impact and compression trauma and were located only on the diaphragmatic surface of the liver, more often in the right half, in the middle third of the organ. These ruptures were linear, co-directional and small in size under various external influences. Central ruptures were formed by impact and compression trauma, were located more often in the middle third of the right side of the liver and were slit-shaped with a longitudinal direction. The size of central ruptures was associated with falls on the stomach and compression trauma. Peripheral ruptures were formed in the case of impact and compression trauma, were located more often in the right half of the liver on its diaphragmatic surface, mainly in the middle third of the organ and were linear with a slanting direction. The relative constancy of the average sizes of peripheral ruptures was noted. Anti-shock ruptures were observed resulting from shock trauma and were located more often in the right side of the liver, on its visceral surface, in the rear third of the organ. They were linear and curvilinear, and longitudinally and obliquely oriented. Ruptures were relatively constant in size with different types of impact.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Dubrovina</LastName>
                    <ForeName>I A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>IA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Gerasimov</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A N</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AN</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Medical Informatics and Statistics of the Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University under Ministry of Health of the Russia, Moscow, Russia, 119991.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Dubrovin</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A I</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AI</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Criminal Law Disciplines, Tver Institute, Moscow Humanitarian and Economic University, Tver, Russia, 170006.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Bychkov</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Aulov</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Mosoyan</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A S</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AS</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine and Law of the Pavlov First St. Petersburg State Medical University of the Ministry of Healthcare of Russia, St. Petersburg, Russia, 197022.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>rus</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Obshchaia kharakteristika morfometricheskikh i morfoskopicheskikh priznakov razryvov pecheni razlichnoĭ lokalizatsii.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Russia (Federation)</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Sud Med Ekspert</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0404546</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0039-4521</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="rus">
            <AbstractText>Цель исследования - сравнительный анализ морфоскопических и морфометрических признаков местных и отдаленных разрывов печени при различных видах внешнего воздействия. Установили, что местные основные разрывы формируются при ударной травме чаще в правой половине печени на ее диафрагмальной поверхности, в передней трети органа. Они линейные и располагаются в продольном направлении. Размеры разрывов возрастают при увеличении силы ударного воздействия. Местные дополнительные разрывы появляются при ударной и компрессионной травме, локализуются исключительно на диафрагмальной поверхности печени, чаще в правой половине, в средней трети органа. Такие разрывы линейные, косонаправленные, размеры их небольшие при различных видах внешнего воздействия. Центральные разрывы формируются при ударной и компрессионной травме, локализуются чаще в средней трети правой половины печени, щелевидные, направление их продольное. Преобладают размеры центральных разрывов при падениях на живот и компрессионной травме. Периферические разрывы образуются при ударной и компрессионной травме, локализуются чаще в правой половине печени на ее диафрагмальной поверхности, преимущественно в средней трети органа, линейные, располагаются в косом направлении. Отметили относительное постоянство средних размеров периферических разрывов. Противоударные разрывы наблюдаются при ударной травме, локализуются чаще в правой половине печени, на ее висцеральной поверхности, в задней трети органа. Они линейные и криволинейные, имеют продольную и косую направленность. Разрывы относительно постоянных размеров при различных видах ударного воздействия.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blunt trauma</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">morphoscopic and morphometric signs of local and distant liver ruptures</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198200</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17116/sudmed20196203121</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

