


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198198</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0039-4521</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>62</Volume>
                    <Issue>3</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Sudebno-meditsinskaia ekspertiza</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Sud. Med. Ekspert.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[Comparative characteristics of injuries to individual body parts of the driver and passengers inside the passenger compartment of a moving vehicle in a traffic accident].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>12-16</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17116/sudmed20196203112</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>The purpose of this study was to investigate the general nature of injuries sustained in a moving passenger car during an accident. The study investigated the nature of injuries in drivers (99 cases) and passengers in the front seat (64), rear right seat (15), rear middle seat (29) and rear left seat (22) who died in an accident due to frontal collision with an obstacle. The general characteristics of the resulting damage were determined with regard to their type, quantity and localization. Drivers were found to have predominantly left-sided injuries to the head and chest, as well as right-sided abdominal and pelvic injuries, frequent neck injuries, smaller limb and permanent foot injuries. The injuries sustained by front seat passengers were characterized mainly by right-sided localization of head and neck injuries, maximum left-sided injury of the upper and lower limbs, and an absence of injuries to the feet. Passengers in the rear right seat were predominantly characterized by right-sided localization of injuries to the head, chest, stomach, pelvis and limbs, an absence of injuries to the feet and a relatively high frequency of damage to the internal organs of the thoracic and abdominal cavities. Passengers in the rear middle seat were characterized by uniform distribution of injuries on the left and right sides of the body, a relatively high frequency of injuries to the head, upper limbs, chest, abdomen and pelvis, a relatively low frequency lower limb injuries and an absence of injuries to the feet. Passengers in the left-hand rear seat were characterized by maximum left-sided localization of injuries to the head, chest and left extremities and minimum traumatization of the internal organs of the thoracic and abdominal cavities.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Bychkov</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Dubrovin</LastName>
                    <ForeName>I A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>IA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Gerasimov</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A N</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AN</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Medical Informatics and Statistics of the of the Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University under Ministry of Health of the Russia, Moscow, Russia, 119991.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Grukhovskiy</LastName>
                    <ForeName>S V</ForeName>
                    <Initials>SV</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Mosoyan</LastName>
                    <ForeName>A S</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AS</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine and Jurisprudence of the Pavlov First St. Petersburg State Medical University of the Ministry of Healthcare of Russia, St. Petersburg, Russia, 197022.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>rus</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Sravnitel'naia kharakteristika povrezhdeniĭ otdel'nykh chasteĭ tela u voditelia i passazhirov vnutri salona dvizhushchegosia avtomobilia pri dorozhno-transportnom proisshestvii.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Russia (Federation)</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Sud Med Ekspert</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0404546</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0039-4521</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="rus">
            <AbstractText>Цель исследования - изучение общего характера повреждений у пострадавших в движущемся легковом автомобиле при дорожно-транспортном происшествии. Изучили характер повреждений у водителей (99 случаев), пассажиров переднего сиденья (64), заднего правого (15), заднего среднего (29) и заднего левого сиденья (22), которые погибли в ДТП в результате фронтального столкновения автомобиля с препятствием. Приведена общая характеристика образующихся повреждений: определены их вид, количество и локализация. Установили, что для водителей характерны преимущественно левосторонняя локализация повреждений головы и груди, а также правосторонняя локализация повреждений живота и таза, частая травматизация шеи, меньшая - конечностей и постоянное повреждение стоп. Для пассажиров переднего сиденья характерны преимущественно правосторонняя локализация повреждений головы, шеи, максимальная левосторонняя травматизация верхних и нижних конечностей, отсутствие повреждений на стопах. Для пассажиров заднего правого сиденья характерны преимущественно правосторонняя локализация повреждений головы, груди, живота, таза и конечностей, отсутствие повреждений на стопах, относительно высокая частота образования повреждений внутренних органов грудной и брюшной полостей. Для пассажиров заднего среднего сиденья характерны равномерное распределение повреждений на левой и правой сторонах тела, относительно высокая частота повреждений головы, верхних конечностей, груди, живота и таза, относительно невысокая частота повреждений нижних конечностей, отсутствие повреждений на стопах. Для пассажиров заднего левого сиденья характерны максимальная левосторонняя локализация повреждений головы, груди и левых конечностей, минимальная травматизация внутренних органов грудной и брюшной полостей.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">general characteristics of victim injuries</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">injuries inside the car interior in an accident</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198198</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17116/sudmed20196203112</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

