


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31198197</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0039-4521</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>62</Volume>
                    <Issue>3</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Sudebno-meditsinskaia ekspertiza</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Sud. Med. Ekspert.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[Morphofunctional vascular changes associated with sudden death in the young].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>9-11</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17116/sudmed2019620319</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Diagnosis of sudden death in the young is based on the results of a set of research methods. Immunohistochemical, histochemical and histochemical methods are fundamental to the diagnosis of hidden forms of connective tissue pathology. These methods allow the sequence of initial and irreversible changes in connective tissue structures to be determined. The aim of this study was to determine the abnormalities of the vascular wall structure when using immunohistochemical and histological methods for the verification of congenital anomalies of various types of vessels, which expand the criteria for the diagnostic detection of individuals with connective tissue dysplasia. These investigation methods allow the diagnosis of hidden forms of congenital connective tissue pathology in the young. The main morphological signs of pathology of the aorta, carotid arteries, coronary and cerebral arteries are the disturbance of structural elements of the connective tissue.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Pigolkin</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Yu I</ForeName>
                    <Initials>YI</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine of the Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University under Ministry of Health of the Russia, Moscow, Russia, 119991; Department of Fundamental Medicine, Far Eastern Federal University, School of Biomedicine, Primorsky Krai, Russia, 690922.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Dolzhanskiy</LastName>
                    <ForeName>O V</ForeName>
                    <Initials>OV</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Pathology and Anatomy Department of Petrovsky National Research Centre of Surgery, Moscow, Russia, 119991.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Reva</LastName>
                    <ForeName>G V</ForeName>
                    <Initials>GV</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Fundamental Medicine, Far Eastern Federal University, School of Biomedicine, Primorsky Krai, Russia, 690922.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Shilova</LastName>
                    <ForeName>M A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>MA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine of the Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University under Ministry of Health of the Russia, Moscow, Russia, 119991.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Globa</LastName>
                    <ForeName>I V</ForeName>
                    <Initials>IV</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Medicine of the Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University under Ministry of Health of the Russia, Moscow, Russia, 119991.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>rus</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Morfofunktsional'nye izmeneniia sosudov pri vnezapnoĭ smerti u lits molodogo vozrasta.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Russia (Federation)</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Sud Med Ekspert</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0404546</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0039-4521</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="rus">
            <AbstractText>Диагностика внезапной смерти лиц молодого возраста складывается из результатов комплекса методов исследования. Иммуногистохимические, гистологические и гистохимические методы являются основополагающими в диагностике скрытых форм патологии соединительной ткани. Эти методы позволяют определить последовательность начальных и необратимых изменений соединительнотканных структур. Цель исследования - установление особенностей строения сосудистой стенки при использовании иммуногистохимического и гистологического методов для верификации врожденных аномалий сосудов различного типа, которые расширяют критерии диагностического выявления лиц с дисплазией соединительной ткани. Данные методы исследования позволяют диагностировать скрытые формы врожденной патологии соединительной ткани у лиц молодого возраста. Основные морфологические признаки патологии аорты, сонных артерий, коронарных и мозговых артерий - нарушение структурных элементов соединительной ткани.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">connective tissue dysplasia</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hidden forms</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vascular abnormalities</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198197</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17116/sudmed2019620319</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

