


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31200424</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0002-5151</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>66</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <MedlineDate>2019 Apr-Jun</MedlineDate>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Revista alergia Mexico (Tecamachalco, Puebla, Mexico : 1993)</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Rev Alerg Mex</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[Food protein-induced enterocolitis syndrome. A case report].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>257-262</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.29262/ram.v66i2.530</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Food protein-induced enterocolitis syndrome or FPIES is a rare, not-IgE-mediated food allergy. The predominant feature is vomit from one to four hours after consuming the causal food.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CASE" NlmCategory="METHODS">An 8-month-old boy, with no family history of allergy, with a personal pathological history of allergy to cow's milk protein. At 7 months of age, he had acute gastroenteritis with mixed shock and, at 8 months of age, he had acute gastroenteritis and moderate dehydration. In both episodes, he had eaten rice before the symptoms started. When infectious etiology and other causes of vomit and dehydration were ruled out, the diagnosis of FPIES, which is secondary to rice protein, was made and confirmed with a patch test.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">FPIES should be considered in the differential diagnosis of recurrent gastroenteritis, especially in severe cases without an identified infectious cause.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>González-Cruz</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Miguel Ángel</ForeName>
                    <Initials>MÁ</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Asociación Médica del Centro Médico ABC, Centro Médico ABC Santa Fe, Servicio de Pediatría, Ciudad de México, México. docmiguelcruz@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Ferreiro-Marín</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Alejandro</ForeName>
                    <Initials>A</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Meave-Cueva</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Luis Guillermo</ForeName>
                    <Initials>LG</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Muriel-Vizcaíno</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Rodolfo</ForeName>
                    <Initials>R</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>spa</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Síndrome de enterocolitis inducida por proteínas de los alimentos. Reporte de caso.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Mexico</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Rev Alerg Mex</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9438824</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0002-5151</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa">
            <AbstractText>Antecedentes: El síndrome de enterocolitis inducida por proteínas de los alimentos es una alergia alimentaria poco frecuente no mediada por IgE. El síntoma principal son los vómitos una a cuatro horas después del consumo del alimento causal. Caso clínico: Varón de ocho meses, sin antecedentes heredofamiliares de alergia, con antecedentes personales patológicos de alergia a la proteína de la leche de vaca. A los siete meses había presentado gastroenteritis aguda con choque mixto y a los ocho meses, gastroenteritis aguda y deshidratación moderada; en ambos eventos hubo consumo de arroz previo al inicio de los síntomas. Al descartar etiología infecciosa y otras causas de vómitos y deshidratación, se formuló el diagnóstico de síndrome de enterocolitis inducida por proteínas de los alimentos, secundario a proteína de arroz, que se corroboró con prueba de parche. Conclusión: El síndrome de enterocolitis inducida por proteínas de los alimentos debe ser considerado en el diagnóstico diferencial de gastroenteritis recurrente, principalmente en cuadros graves sin causa infecciosa identificada.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Food allergy</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Food protein-induced enterocolitis syndrome</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Not-IgE-mediated food allergy</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200424</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29262/ram.v66i2.530</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

