


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31200195</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-7123</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>278</Volume>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                        <Day>04</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Psychiatry research</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Psychiatry Res</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Explicit emotional memory biases in mood disorders: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>162-172</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0165-1781(19)30768-1</ELocationID>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.psychres.2019.06.003</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Research suggests that major depressive disorder (MDD) and bipolar disorder (BD) are both associated with unique emotional memory (EM) biases. To better elucidate the EM phenotypes of these disorders, we systematically reviewed the literature on non-autobiographical explicit EM biases in individuals with MDD and BD compared to healthy controls. The following databases were searched: Cochrane, Embase, HAPI, LILACs, Medline, PsycInfo and Web of Science. Grey literature and hand searches were also performed. Fourteen studies met full eligibility criteria. Eleven studies included data from an MDD sample (10 during acute depression, 1 during euthymia) and 3 studies included data from a BD sample (2 during acute mood episodes, 1 during euthymia). Only 3 of the studies in acute depression revealed a negative explicit EM bias. One study in MDD during euthymia revealed an EM deficit for negative stimuli. One of the two studies in BD (type I; BD-I) during an acute mood episode revealed a positive explicit EM bias, while the other showed no bias. One study in BD during euthymia showed an EM deficit for negative stimuli. Overall, this review concludes that current empirical evidence does not readily support the existence of an explicit EM bias in MDD during acute depression. The identification and implications of potential moderating factors on explicit EM performance in MDD and BD during both illness stages are discussed.</AbstractText>
                <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>J M Bogie</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Bryce</ForeName>
                    <Initials>B</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Neuroscience Graduate Program, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada; Department of Psychiatry and Behavioural Neurosciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada; Mood Disorders Program, St. Joseph's Healthcare Hamilton, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Persaud</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Monisha R</ForeName>
                    <Initials>MR</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Smith</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Denise</ForeName>
                    <Initials>D</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Health Sciences Library, Faculty of Health Sciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Kapczinski</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Flávio P</ForeName>
                    <Initials>FP</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Neuroscience Graduate Program, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada; Department of Psychiatry and Behavioural Neurosciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada; Mood Disorders Program, St. Joseph's Healthcare Hamilton, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada; Department of Psychiatry, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Frey</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Benicio N</ForeName>
                    <Initials>BN</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Neuroscience Graduate Program, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada; Department of Psychiatry and Behavioural Neurosciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada; Mood Disorders Program, St. Joseph's Healthcare Hamilton, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada; Women's Health Concerns Clinic, St. Joseph's Healthcare Hamilton, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada. Electronic address: freybn@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>04</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Ireland</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Psychiatry Res</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>7911385</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0165-1781</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bipolar disorder</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Emotion</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Emotional memory</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Major depressive disorder</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mood-congruent memory</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic review</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>04</Month>
                <Day>03</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>02</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>03</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200195</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0165-1781(19)30768-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2019.06.003</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

