


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31200182</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-8630</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>246</Volume>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                        <Day>11</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Journal of environmental management</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>J. Environ. Manage.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Management feasibility of established invasive plant species in Queensland, Australia: A stakeholders' perspective.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>484-495</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0301-4797(19)30662-0</ELocationID>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jenvman.2019.05.052</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Managing and monitoring invasive alien species (IAS) is costly, and because resources are limited, prioritization decisions are required for planning and management. We present findings on plant pest prioritization for 63 established invader species of natural and grazing ecosystems of Queensland, Australia. We used an expert elicitation approach to assess risk (species occurrence, spread, and impact) and feasibility of control for each IAS. We elicit semi-quantitative responses from diverse expert stakeholders to score IAS on three management approaches (biocontrol, chemical and mechanical) in relation to cost, effectiveness and practicality, and incorporate uncertainty in expert inputs and model outputs. In the process, we look for promising management opportunities as well as seek general trends across species' ecological groups and management methods. Stakeholders were cautiously optimistic about the feasibility of managing IAS. Taking into consideration all factors, the overall feasibility of control was uncorrelated with the stakeholders' level of confidence. However, within individual management criterion, positive trend was observed for the same bivariate traits for chemical control, and negative trends for biocontrol and mechanical controls. Utility and confidence in IAS management options were in the order: chemical &gt; biocontrol = mechanical, with practicality and effectiveness being the main driver components. Management feasibility differed significantly between IAS life forms but not between habitats invaded. Lastly, we combined IAS risk assessment and management feasibility scores to create a risk matrix to guide policy goals (i.e. eradication, spread containment, protection of sensitive sites, targeted control, site management, monitoring, and limited action). The matrix identifies promising species to target for each of these policy outcomes. Overall, our general approach illustrates (i) the importance of understanding the feasibility of IAS control actions and the factors that drive it, and (ii) demonstrates how quantifying management feasibility can be used to enhance traditional risk assessment rankings to improve policy outcomes.</AbstractText>
                <CopyrightInformation>Crown Copyright © 2019. Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Osunkoya</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Olusegun O</ForeName>
                    <Initials>OO</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Invasive Plant and Animal Science Unit, Biosecurity Sciences, Queensland Department of Agriculture and Fisheries, Eco-sciences Precinct, Brisbane, QLD 4102, Australia. Electronic address: olusegun.osunkoya@daf.qld.gov.au.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Froese</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Jens G</ForeName>
                    <Initials>JG</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>CSIRO Health and Biosecurity, Eco-sciences Precinct, Brisbane, QLD 4102, Australia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Nicol</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Sam</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>CSIRO Land and Water, Eco-sciences Precinct, Brisbane, QLD 4102, Australia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>11</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>England</Country>
            <MedlineTA>J Environ Manage</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0401664</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0301-4797</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Australia</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Expert elicitation</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Management feasibility</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pest risk assessment</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prioritization</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stakeholders</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weed control options</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2018</Year>
                <Month>12</Month>
                <Day>16</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>02</Month>
                <Day>26</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>10</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200182</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0301-4797(19)30662-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2019.05.052</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

