


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31200107</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-7544</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                        <Day>11</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Neuroscience</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Neuroscience</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Fronto-parietal Brain Areas Contribute to the Online Control of Posture during a Continuous Balance Task.</ArticleTitle>
            <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0306-4522(19)30394-X</ELocationID>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.neuroscience.2019.05.063</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Neuroimaging studies have provided evidence for the involvement of frontal and parietal cortices in postural control. However, the specific role of these brain areas for postural control remain to be known. In this study, we investigated the effects of disruptive TMS over supplementary motor areas (SMA) during challenging continuous balance task in healthy young adults. We hypothesized that a virtual lesion of SMA will alter activation within the brain network identified using electroencephalography (EEG) and impair performance of the postural task. Twenty healthy young adults received either continuous theta burst stimulation (cTBS) or sham stimulation over SMA followed by the performance of a continuous balance task with or without somatosensory input distortion created by sway-referencing the support surface. cTBS over SMA compared to sham stimulation showed a smaller increase in RMS COP as the difficulty of continuous balance task increased suggestive of altered postural control mechanisms to find a stable solution under challenging sensory conditions. Consistent with earlier studies, we found sources of EEG activation within anterior cingulate (AC), cingulate gyrus (CG), bilateral posterior parietal regions (LPP and RPP) during the balance task. Importantly, cTBS over SMA compared to sham stimulation altered EEG power within the identified fronto-parietal regions. These findings suggest that the changes in activation within distant fronto-parietal brain areas following cTBS over SMA contributed to the altered postural behavior. Our study confirms a critical role of AC, CG, and both PPC regions in calibrating online postural responses during a challenging continuous balance task.</AbstractText>
                <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2019. Published by Elsevier Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Goel</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Rahul</ForeName>
                    <Initials>R</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Center for Neuromotor and Biomechanics Research, Department of Health and Human Performance, University of Houston, Houston, Texas.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Nakagome</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Sho</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Laboratory for Noninvasive Brain-Machine Interface Systems, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Houston, Houston, Texas.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Rao</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Nishant</ForeName>
                    <Initials>N</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Center for Neuromotor and Biomechanics Research, Department of Health and Human Performance, University of Houston, Houston, Texas.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Paloski</LastName>
                    <ForeName>William H</ForeName>
                    <Initials>WH</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Human Research Program, Johnson Space Center, NASA, Houston, Texas.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Contreras-Vidal</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Jose L</ForeName>
                    <Initials>JL</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Laboratory for Noninvasive Brain-Machine Interface Systems, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Houston, Houston, Texas. Electronic address: jlcontr2@central.uh.edu.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Parikh</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Pranav J</ForeName>
                    <Initials>PJ</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Center for Neuromotor and Biomechanics Research, Department of Health and Human Performance, University of Houston, Houston, Texas. Electronic address: pjparikh2@uh.edu.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>11</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Neuroscience</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>7605074</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0306-4522</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>02</Month>
                <Day>05</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>30</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>31</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200107</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0306-4522(19)30394-X</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroscience.2019.05.063</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

