


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31200082</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0038</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                        <Day>11</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Gene</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Gene</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>PHACTR1 haplotypes are associated with carotid plaque presence and affect PHACTR1 mRNA expression in carotid plaque tissue.</ArticleTitle>
            <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0378-1119(19)30580-3</ELocationID>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.gene.2019.06.020</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Carotid plaque is a hallmark of advanced carotid atherosclerosis and there is evidence of phosphatase and actin regulator 1 (PHACTR1) involvement in the processes that lead to atherosclerosis. PHACTR1 intronic variants have been associated with coronary artery disease and carotid dissection. Up to date the PHACTR1 haplotypes were not investigated in association with carotid plaque presence (CPP). So, the aims of this study were to investigate possible association of PHACTR1 haplotypes inferred from the intronic variants rs9349379, rs2026458 and rs2876300 with CPP in patients with advanced carotid atherosclerosis and to analyze their possible effect on PHACTR1 relative mRNA expression in carotid plaque tissue specimens.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study group consisted of 501 patients with evidence of carotid plaque presence admitted for carotid endarterectomy and 310 healthy controls. PHACTR1 rs9349379, rs2026458, rs2876300 and relative mRNA expression were detected by TaqMan® technology.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We have found significant and independent association of haplotype ACA with the CPP, compared to the referent haplotype GTA (adjusted OR = 1.54 95% CI = 1.07-2.21, p = 0.02). The OR was adjusted for gender, age, BMI, hypertension and total cholesterol. The relative expression of PHACTR1 mRNA in carotid plaque tissue proved to be significantly higher in carriers of the ACG haplotype compared to the referent haplotype GTA (p = 0.03).</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results suggest that PHACTR1 haplotypes inferred from the variants rs9349379, rs2026458 and rs2876300 affect PHACTR1 mRNA and bear the risk for CPP in patients with advanced carotid atherosclerosis. Further replication and validation studies are inevitable.</AbstractText>
                <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2018. Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Kuveljic</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Jovana</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Vinca Institute of Nuclear Sciences, Laboratory for Radiobiology and Molecular Genetics, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia. Electronic address: jovana@vinca.rs.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Djuric</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Tamara</ForeName>
                    <Initials>T</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Vinca Institute of Nuclear Sciences, Laboratory for Radiobiology and Molecular Genetics, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia. Electronic address: tamariska@vinca.rs.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Stankovic</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Aleksandra</ForeName>
                    <Initials>A</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Vinca Institute of Nuclear Sciences, Laboratory for Radiobiology and Molecular Genetics, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia. Electronic address: alexas@vinca.rs.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Koncar</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Igor</ForeName>
                    <Initials>I</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Vascular and Endovascular Surgery, Faculty of Medicine, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia; Department of Vascular and Endovascular Surgery, Clinical Center of Serbia, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Alavantic</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Dragan</ForeName>
                    <Initials>D</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Vinca Institute of Nuclear Sciences, Laboratory for Radiobiology and Molecular Genetics, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia. Electronic address: adragan@vinca.rs.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Zivkovic</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Maja</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Vinca Institute of Nuclear Sciences, Laboratory for Radiobiology and Molecular Genetics, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia. Electronic address: majaz@vinca.rs.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>11</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Netherlands</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Gene</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>7706761</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0378-1119</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atherosclerosis</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carotid plaque</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Haplotype</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PHACTR1</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mRNA expression</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>02</Month>
                <Day>07</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>04</Month>
                <Day>25</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>10</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200082</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0378-1119(19)30580-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gene.2019.06.020</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

