


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31199920</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1525-2191</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                        <Day>11</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>The American journal of pathology</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Am. J. Pathol.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Diverse Consequences in Liver Injury in Mice with Different Autophagy Functional Status Treated with Alcohol.</ArticleTitle>
            <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0002-9440(19)30094-X</ELocationID>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ajpath.2019.05.011</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Alcoholic fatty liver disease is often complicated by other pathological insults, such as viral infection or high fat diet. Autophagy plays a homeostatic role in the liver but can be compromised by alcohol, high fat diet, or viral infection, which in turn affect the disease process caused by these etiologies. To understand the full impact of autophagy modulation on alcohol-induced liver injury, several genetic models of autophagy deficiency, which have different levels of functional alterations, were examined following acute binge or chronic-plus-binge treatment. Alcohol given in either mode to the liver-specific inducible Atg7-deficient mice shortly after the induction of Atg7 deletion had an elevated liver injury, indicating the protective role of autophagy. Constitutive hepatic Atg7 deficient mice, in which Atg7 was deleted in embryos, were more susceptible to chronic-plus-binge but not to acute alcohol treatment. Constitutive hepatic Atg5 deficient mice, in which Atg5 was deleted in embryos, were more prone to acute alcohol treatment, but liver injury were surprisingly improved in the chronic-plus-binge regime. A prolonged autophagy deficiency may complicate the hepatic response to alcohol treatment, likely in part due to endogenous liver injury. The complexity of the relationship between autophagy deficiency and alcohol-induced liver injury can thus be affected by the timing of autophagy dysfunction, the exact autophagy gene being affected, and the alcohol treatment regime.</AbstractText>
                <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2019. Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Yan</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Shengmin</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Indiana University School of Medicine, Indianapolis, Indiana.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Zhou</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Jun</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Indiana University School of Medicine, Indianapolis, Indiana; Departments of Minimal Invasive Surgery.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Chen</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Xiaoyun</ForeName>
                    <Initials>X</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Indiana University School of Medicine, Indianapolis, Indiana.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Dong</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Zheng</ForeName>
                    <Initials>Z</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Nephrology, The Second Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China; Department of Cell Biology and Anatomy, Medical College of Georgia and Charlie Norwood VA Medical Center, Augusta, Georgia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Yin</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Xiao-Ming</ForeName>
                    <Initials>XM</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Indiana University School of Medicine, Indianapolis, Indiana; Nephrology, The Second Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China. Electronic address: xmyin@iu.edu.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>11</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Am J Pathol</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0370502</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0002-9440</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>02</Month>
                <Day>01</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>01</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>07</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31199920</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0002-9440(19)30094-X</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajpath.2019.05.011</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

