


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31199764</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2191-0286</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                        <Day>13</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Journal of basic and clinical physiology and pharmacology</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>J Basic Clin Physiol Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Involvement of proinflammatory cytokines and metallothionein in the repairing of arsenic-mediated uterine tissue damage by curcumin.</ArticleTitle>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1515/jbcpp-2017-0179</ELocationID>
            <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">/j/jbcpp.ahead-of-print/jbcpp-2017-0179/jbcpp-2017-0179.xml</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Background Curcumin is extensively used as a therapeutic intervention for treating several ailments. The antioxidant curcumin has an anti-inflammatory and chelating property with arsenic to exhibit a strong therapeutic effect on reproductive organs. This study was undertaken to describe the protective effect of noninvasive administration of curcumin against sodium-arsenite-mediated uterine hazards in female Wistar rats. Methods Twenty-four female Wistar rats were randomly divided into four groups. The treatment was continued for 8 days and given orally sodium arsenite (10 mg/kg body weight) in combination with curcumin (20 mg/kg body weight). Results Our evaluation revealed that 8 days of sodium arsenite (10 mg/kg body weight) treatment reduced the activities of the uterine enzymatic antioxidants superoxide dismutase, catalase, and peroxidase. Blood levels of vitamin B12 and folic acid decreased followed by an increased serum lactate dehydrogenase, homocysteine level, and hepatic metallothionein-1 in arsenic-treated rats. Necrosis of uterine tissue along with the disruption of ovarian steroidogenesis was marked in arsenic-treated rats with an upregulation of uterine NF-κB and IL-6 along with a raised level of serum TNF-α. Oral administration of curcumin (20 mg/kg body weight/day) in arsenic-treated rats significantly reinstated these alterations of the antioxidant system followed by an improvement of ovarian steroidogenesis and the circulating level of B12 and folate along with the downregulation of serum homocysteine, metallothionein-1, and cytokines. Conclusions The findings of this study clearly and strongly elucidated that arsenic-induced oxidative stress in uterus is linked to an alteration of inflammation-signaling biomarkers and these have been protected through the co-administration of curcumin due to its anti-inflammatory, free radical scavenging, and antioxidant activity by the possible regulation of an S-adenosine methionine pool.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Perveen</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Hasina</ForeName>
                    <Initials>H</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Laboratory Science and Management, and Clinical Nutrition and Dietetics Division, UGC Innovative Department, Vidyasagar University, Midnapore, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Chattopadhyay</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Sandip</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Laboratory Science and Management, and Clinical Nutrition and Dietetics Division, UGC Innovative Department, Vidyasagar University, Midnapore-721102, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Maity</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Moulima</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Laboratory Science and Management, and Clinical Nutrition and Dietetics Division, UGC Innovative Department, Vidyasagar University, Midnapore, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Dash</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Moumita</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Laboratory Science and Management, and Clinical Nutrition and Dietetics Division, UGC Innovative Department, Vidyasagar University, Midnapore, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Islam</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Syed Sirajul</ForeName>
                    <Initials>SS</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry and Chemical Technology, Vidyasagar University, Midnapore, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>13</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Germany</Country>
            <MedlineTA>J Basic Clin Physiol Pharmacol</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9101750</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0792-6855</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SAM</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">arsenic</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">curcumin</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ovarian steroidogenesis</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">uterine oxidative stress</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2017</Year>
                <Month>10</Month>
                <Day>22</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>01</Month>
                <Day>18</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31199764</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/jbcpp-2017-0179</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">/j/jbcpp.ahead-of-print/jbcpp-2017-0179/jbcpp-2017-0179.xml</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

