


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Data-Review" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31199752</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0363-6771</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>67</Volume>
                    <Issue>3</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <MedlineDate>2019 May-Jun</MedlineDate>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>General dentistry</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Gen Dent</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>The influence of impression coping splinting on the accuracy of the open-tray technique.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>e5-e9</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>The objective of this study was to examine the effect of splinting of the impression copings on the accuracy of the cast when the open-tray technique is used. An epoxy master cast with 3 implants was fabricated. The first 2 implants were parallel to each other and perpendicular to the horizontal plane (implants A and B), and the third implant (implant C) had a 25-degree inclination. A passively fitting metal framework that was fabricated over this master cast was used to measure accuracy of fit. Ten casts were fabricated from this epoxy resin master cast with the use of polyether material and the open-tray technique. For the first 5 casts, the impression copings were splinted with dental floss and autopolymerizing acrylic resin; in the next 5 casts, the impression copings were not splinted. The metal framework in the master cast was fixed in the new specimens, and the microgap between this prosthesis and the implant analogs was evaluated. The specimens were observed under an optical microscope, and microgap measurements were made on photographs taken at a standardized magnification of 40×. The inclined implant C had the smallest mean microgap among the 3 implants, but the differences were not statistically significant. Microgaps for all 3 implants were smaller when they were splinted, but the difference from the mean of the nonsplinted counterpart was statistically significant only for the inclined implant. The results suggest that there is no clinical advantage in splinting the impression copings for parallel implants. On the other hand, when the implants are not parallel, splinting of the impression copings can result in greater accuracy of the fabricated cast.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Kavadia</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Visiliki</ForeName>
                    <Initials>V</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Kourtis</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Stefanos</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Zoidis</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Panagiotis</ForeName>
                    <Initials>P</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Sarafianou</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Aspasia</ForeName>
                    <Initials>A</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Gen Dent</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>7610466</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0363-6771</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31199752</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

