


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Data-Review" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31199744</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0363-6771</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>67</Volume>
                    <Issue>3</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <MedlineDate>2019 May-Jun</MedlineDate>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>General dentistry</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Gen Dent</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Immediate restoration after mineral trioxide aggregate pulpotomy with amalgam condensation: an in vitro study.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>47-51</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Mineral trioxide aggregate (MTA) pulpotomy may be an alternative to root canal therapy, with reported success rates as high as 85%. However, little technique-specific information has been reported regarding MTA placement in 1 visit. The purpose of this study was to evaluate different placement methods for MTA and resin-modified glass ionomer (RMGI) cement before immediate restoration with amalgam. Forty pulpotomized extracted third molars were randomly divided into 4 groups, and moist cotton was used to simulate pulp tissue in all teeth. In group 1, cotton was placed over the entire pulp chamber floor and in each canal orifice, and MTA was placed over the cotton. The procedure for group 2 was the same as that for group 1 except that a layer of RMGI was placed over the MTA. In group 3, cotton was placed in the canal orifices only, a layer of MTA was placed only over the cotton in the orifices, and RMGI was layered over the MTA and pulp chamber floor. The procedure for group 4 was the same as that for group 3 except that RMGI was placed over the MTA but not on the pulpal floor. Each of these procedures was followed by amalgam condensation. After a 7-day setting period, restored teeth were sectioned mesiodistally, photographed, measured, and evaluated for disturbance of the MTA-restoration junction. The study findings showed that the MTA layer was disturbed in 40% of the specimens in group 1, whereas 10%-20% of specimens in groups 2 through 4 demonstrated disturbed MTA. Analysis with a Pearson chi-square test indicated that the difference between group 1 and groups 2 through 4 was statistically significant (P &lt; 0.05), but there was no significant difference (P &gt; 0.05) between groups 2, 3, and 4. Group 3, in which MTA was placed over each canal orifice and RMGI was placed over the entire pulpal floor, performed best--only 10% of specimens exhibited deformed MTA. The findings suggest that RMGI may protect initially placed MTA during amalgam condensation.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Lam</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Winnie</ForeName>
                    <Initials>W</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Frick</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Kenneth J</ForeName>
                    <Initials>KJ</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Walker</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Mary P</ForeName>
                    <Initials>MP</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Gen Dent</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>7610466</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0363-6771</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest pertaining to any of the products or companies discussed in this article.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31199744</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

