


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31199637</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1520-5118</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                        <Day>14</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Journal of agricultural and food chemistry</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>J. Agric. Food Chem.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Novel Semi-IPN Nanocomposites with Functions of both Nutrient Slow-Release and Water Retention Part II: Effects on Soil Fertility and Tomato Quality.</ArticleTitle>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acs.jafc.9b00889</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>So far, effects of semi-interpenetrating polymer network (semi-IPN) composites with functions of both nutrient slow-release and water retention on soil physicochemical properties, yield and quality of crops have not been studied. In Part I of this paper, super absorbent polymers SAPWS (grafting wheat straw (WS) to poly(acrylic-co-acrylamide), which is WS-g-P(AA-co-AM)) and SAPHEC (HEC (hydroxyethyl cellulose)-g-P(AA-co-AM)), and their semi-IPN nanocomposites SI-PSRF/SAPWS and SI-PSRF/SAPHEC (formed by chemical bonding of SAPWS or SAPHEC with PSRF (NPK-containing polymeric slow-release fertilizer )) were prepared, their microstructures and degradation performances were systematically studied. In this study, effects of these two nanocomposites on soil physicochemical properties, crop yield and quality, as well as soil fertility, especially the relationships between these effects and the degradation performances of the materials themselves were investigated by a pot experiment of tomato. Results show that SI-PSRF/SAP nanocomposites can regulate the pH values of weak alkaline soils to close to 7.0. And the changes of soil pH values, in our study, are basically synchronized with the degradation rates of SI-PSRF/SAP, the higher the degradation rate of SI-PSRF/SAP, the lower the pH value of the alkaline soil treated. Compared with PSRF+SAP (the simple physically mixed system of PSRF and SAP) and PSRF, during the whole growth period of tomato, SI-PSRF/SAP treatments have the lowest nitrogen release amounts, 4.74 g for SI-PSRF/SAPWS and 4.88 g for SI-PSRF/SAPHEC, the highest nitrogen contents of soils after day 40, and the highest nitrogen contents of plants, on day 100, 1.16 g and 1.68 g for SI-PSRF/SAPWS, 1.26 g and 1.86 g for SI-PSRF/SAPHEC. While for PSRF+SAPWS, PSRF+SAPHEC and PSRF, they are 5.16 g, 0.81g, 0.63g and 5.26g, 0.87g, 0.66g and 5.17g, 0.63g, 0.52g, respectively. There is a significant positive correlation between the material degradation rates and their nitrogen release amounts in this study, while SI-PSRF/SAP systems have the highest correlation coefficient 0.950. In addition, compared to the control blank, SI-PSRF/SAP system significantly increases tomato yield, 270.1% for SI-PSRF/SAPWS and 301.7% for SI-PSRF/SAPHEC. Compared with PSRF+SAP, SI-PSRF/SAP system can make the soil treated become a high-quality soil by influencing the soil pH value, conductivity, cation exchange capacity, the contents of nitrogen, phosphorus, organic carbon and active organic carbon, which have significant impacts on soil quality. The chemical-bonded functional nanocomposites with semi-IPN three-dimensional network structures formed by hydrogen-bonding interactions among functional groups of their components can more efficiently improve soil fertility, increase soil nutrient supply capacity, and promote plants growth and development, as well as solve the environmental pollution caused by traditional fertilizers. The technology reported in this paper is simple and feasible for large-scale production of fertilizer with both water retention and nutrient slow-release, even nanofertilizer, so has great application potential.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Zhao</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Haidong</ForeName>
                    <Initials>H</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Song</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Jiang</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Zhao</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Guizhe</ForeName>
                    <Initials>G</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Xiang</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Yang</ForeName>
                    <Initials>Y</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Liu</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Yaqing</ForeName>
                    <Initials>Y</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>14</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>J Agric Food Chem</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0374755</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0021-8561</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31199637</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jafc.9b00889</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

