


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31200418</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0002-5151</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>66</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <MedlineDate>2019 Apr-Jun</MedlineDate>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Revista alergia Mexico (Tecamachalco, Puebla, Mexico : 1993)</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Rev Alerg Mex</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>[Epidemiological study on atopic dermatitis in Mexico].</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>192-204</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.29262/ram.v66i2.591</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">There is limited epidemiological information on the treatment of atopic dermatitis (AD) from specialist physicians in Mexico.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To know the criteria that is used by specialists in Mexico to diagnose and treat AD.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">An observational, descriptive and cross-sectional study, which was authorized by the ethics committee, was carried out through an electronic survey.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">114 surveys were carried out; 56% of the participants were allergists, 38% were dermatologists and 5% were pediatricians. It was identified that 54% used clinical criteria for the diagnosis of AD and 42% used the criteria of Hanifin-Rajka as a diagnostic complement; 38% requested total and/or specific IgE, blood biometry and blood chemistry tests. They recount that 90% of patients under the age of 18 had mild AD, 8% had moderate AD and 2% had severe AD; and, in patients over the age of 18, 89% had mild AD, 6% had moderate AD and 5% had severe AD. The patients' care was multidisciplinary, since 57% of the survey respondents requested assessments combined with ophthalmology, dermatology and allergology.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Knowledge of the disease will lead to a better control of the disease. The challenge is to have a patient registry, update treatment guidelines, consider comorbidities and have therapeutic options for its control.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Herrera-Sánchez</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Diana Andrea</ForeName>
                    <Initials>DA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Instituto Mexicano del Seguro Social, Centro Médico Nacional Siglo XXI, Hospital de Especialidades, Ciudad de México, México. dianaaherrera@outlook.com.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Hernández-Ojeda</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Mariana</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Vivas-Rosales</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Irving Jesús</ForeName>
                    <Initials>IJ</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>spa</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>Estudio epidemiológico sobre dermatitis atópica en México.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Mexico</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Rev Alerg Mex</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9438824</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0002-5151</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa">
            <AbstractText>Antecedentes: Existe escasa información epidemiológica sobre el tratamiento de la dermatitis atópica (DA) por parte de los médicos especialistas en México. Objetivo: Conocer los criterios utilizados para el diagnóstico y tratamiento de la DA por los especialistas en México. Método: Estudio observacional, descriptivo y transversal, autorizado por el comité de ética, mediante una encuesta electrónica. Resultados: Se realizaron 114 encuestas, 56 % de los participantes fueron alergólogos, 38 % dermatólogos y 5 % pediatras. Se identificó que 54 % utilizaba criterios clínicos para realizar el diagnóstico de DA y 42 %, los criterios de Hanifin-Rajka; como complemento diagnóstico, 38 % solicitaba IgE total o específica, biometría hemática y química sanguínea. Los encuestados refirieron que 90 % de los menores de 18 años presentaba DA leve, 8 % moderada y 2 % grave; y los mayores de esa edad, 89 % leve, 6 % moderada y 5 % grave. La atención del paciente era multidisciplinaria, ya que 57 % de los encuestados solicitaba valoraciones conjuntas con oftalmología, dermatología y alergología. Conclusión: El conocimiento de la DA propiciará un mejor control de la enfermedad. El reto es contar con un registro de pacientes, actualizar las guías de tratamiento, considerar comorbilidades y contar con opciones terapéuticas para su control.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atopic dermatitis</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eczematous skin diseases</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epidemiology</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200418</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29262/ram.v66i2.591</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

