


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31200326</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-4758</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>71</Volume>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2019</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                        <Day>11</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>The International journal on drug policy</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Int. J. Drug Policy</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Overview of &quot;home&quot; cultivation policies and the case for community-based cannabis supply.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>36-46</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0955-3959(19)30143-4</ELocationID>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.drugpo.2019.05.021</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Cannabis policies should be relevant to communities most impacted by them. Home cultivation policies can engage people who grow cannabis and build on their motivation to supply a safe product. This paper aims to examine the laws pertaining to &quot;home&quot; (i.e. personal, small-scale) cannabis cultivation internationally and their different aspects, and to discuss the potential of these policies to be expanded into community-level cannabis supply models.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We reviewed relevant laws and regulations in states/countries that legalised, decriminalised or applied other non-prohibitive approaches to home cannabis cultivation.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Non-prohibitive approaches to home cannabis cultivation have been adopted in at least 27 jurisdictions. Twelve jurisdictions &quot;de jure&quot; legalised home cultivation (three U.S. states and Antigua and Barbuda legalised only home cultivation; six U.S. states, Uruguay and Canada legalised commercial sales as well). Eight states/countries &quot;de facto&quot; (Belgium, the Netherlands) or &quot;de jure&quot; decriminalised it (Czech Republic, Spain, Jamaica, and three Australian states). &quot;De jure&quot; depenalisation was in place in Chile and Brazil and recent court rulings yielded &quot;de facto&quot; depenalisation or &quot;de facto&quot; legalisation in five other jurisdictions (South Africa, Mexico, Colombia, Costa Rica and Georgia). Varying number of plants (per person and per property) and the circumstances of cultivation were in place. The key limitations of the regulations included (i) possession thresholds for the produce from home cultivations, (ii) rules about sharing the produce, and (iii) potentially disproportionate sanctions for non-authorised behaviours. Despite currently being limited, home cultivation policies might have the capacity to engage cannabis networks that already exist in the community and like that, enhance their participation in legitimate policy schemes.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Rules around pooled cultivation and sharing could be made fit for purpose to accommodate community supply of cannabis. Home cultivation policies could serve as a basis for community-level cannabis supply models and as such, for more inclusive cannabis policies.</AbstractText>
                <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Belackova</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Vendula</ForeName>
                    <Initials>V</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>ResAd - Research and Development, Ltd., Sokolovska 79/81, Prague 8, 186 00, Czech Republic; Uniting Medically Supervised Injecting Centre, Sydney, Australia; Drug Policy Modelling Program, Social Policy Research Centre, University of New South Wales, Australia. Electronic address: belackova.vendula@resad.cz.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Roubalova Stefunkova</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Michaela</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Institute of Criminology and Social Prevention, Prague, Czech Republic.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>van de Ven</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Katinka</ForeName>
                    <Initials>K</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Drug Policy Modelling Program, Social Policy Research Centre, University of New South Wales, Australia; Human Enhancement Drugs Network (HEDN), Australia; School of Humanities, Arts, Social Sciences and Education, UNE, Armidale, NSW, Australia. Electronic address: https://twitter.com/@KatinkavandeVen.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>06</Month>
                <Day>11</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Netherlands</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Int J Drug Policy</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9014759</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0955-3959</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cannabis legalisation</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cannabis policy</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community supply</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community-level policy</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Home/small-scale cannabis cultivation</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2018</Year>
                <Month>10</Month>
                <Day>24</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>03</Month>
                <Day>28</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>20</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200326</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0955-3959(19)30143-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugpo.2019.05.021</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

