


<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">31200417</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0002-5151</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>66</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <MedlineDate>2019 Apr-Jun</MedlineDate>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Revista alergia Mexico (Tecamachalco, Puebla, Mexico : 1993)</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Rev Alerg Mex</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>The role of the fern test in the treatment of rhinitis.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>184-191</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.29262/ram.v66i2.544</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The fern test is a method for assessing the characteristics of the nasal section in the treatment of patients with mucous dysfunction of the airway.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this study was to investigate the role of the fern test in patients with rhinitis and to assess the classification of each type of rhinitis (types I-IV) in clinical practice.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional study, which included consecutive patients from a third level Rhinology Unit, worked with 182 patients with rhinitis and 30 healthy subjects as control. The patients were subdivided according to their type of rhinitis: allergic rhinitis (59), infectious rhinitis (32), polyps (31), NARES (Non-allergic rhinitis with eosinophilia syndrome) (30) and NARNE (non-allergic rhinitis with neutrophils) (30).</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The control subjects had only type I or II rhinitis, whereas patients with rhinitis usually showed type III or IV. Allergic rhinitis and nasal polyps had the most serious deterioration according to the fern test (type IV).</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The fern test is effective for assessing mucus alterations in patients with rhinitis and it could be included as a new parameter in the study of rhinitis as a potential biomarker of the function of damaged epithelial cells.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Gelardi</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Matteo</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>University of Bari Aldo Moro, Department of Basic Medical Science, Neuroscience and Sensory Organs, Bari, Italy. gio.cip@libero.it.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Porro</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName>
                    <Initials>G</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Quaranta</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Nicola</ForeName>
                    <Initials>N</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Sterlicchio</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Brigida</ForeName>
                    <Initials>B</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Silvestri</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Michela</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Ciprandi</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Giorgio</ForeName>
                    <Initials>G</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <VernacularTitle>El papel de la prueba de “helecho” en el tratamiento de la rinitis.</VernacularTitle>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Mexico</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Rev Alerg Mex</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9438824</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0002-5151</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa">
            <AbstractText>Antecedentes: La prueba de “helecho” es un método que sirve para evaluar las características de la secreción nasal en el tratamiento de pacientes con disfunción de la mocosa de la vía aérea. Objetivo: El objetivo del presente estudio fue investigar el papel de la prueba de helecho en pacientes con rinitis y evaluar la clasificación de cada tipo de rinitis (tipos I a IV) en la práctica clínica. Métodos: Estudio transversal en el que se incluyeron pacientes consecutivos de una unidad de rinología de tercer nivel. Se incluyeron 182 pacientes con rinitis y 30 sujetos sanos como controles. Los pacientes se subdividieron según el tipo de rinitis: alérgica (59), infecciosa (32), pólipos (31), rinitis eosinofílica no alérgica (30) y rinitis no alérgica con neutrófilos (30). Resultados: Los sujetos control solo presentaron rinitis tipo I o II, mientras que los pacientes con rinitis generalmente mostraban tipo III o IV. La rinitis alérgica y los pólipos nasales tuvieron el deterioro más grave según la prueba de helecho (tipo IV). Conclusiones: La prueba de helecho es efectiva para evaluar las alteraciones del moco en pacientes con rinitis y podría incluirse como un nuevo parámetro en el estudio de la rinitis como biomarcador potencial de la función de las células epiteliales dañadas.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fern test</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation of the mucosa</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rhinitis</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2019</Year>
                <Month>6</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200417</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29262/ram.v66i2.544</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

